<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="temp.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?><news xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="temp.xsd">
<current_affairs>
    <article>
	<headline>Kerala CM Pinarayi Vijayan lashes out at ‘axis’ against China
	</headline><description>Vijayan said CPI(M) was not for any political alliance with Congress, which was in tune with the party's central comittee resolution in this regard at Kolkota.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Senior CPI(M) leader and Kerala Chief Minister Pinarayi Vijayan on Saturday alleged that India was becoming a strategic partner of the US in that country’s effort to form a larger defence alliance against China, “which is as per interest of RSS.”“China is emerging as a big power in the world… India is becoming a strategic partner of the US in their effort to form a larger defence alliance against China,” he said. “This is as per the interest of RSS. The aim of RSS is to build an axis of countries like US, India and Israel against China,” Vijayan said, inaugurating the CPI(M) district committee meeting in Kannur. CPI(M) state Secretary Kodiyeri Balakrishnan had triggered a row earlier this month after he remarked that an axis of countries like US, Japan, Australia and India has taken shape for attacking China from all sides.The BJP in Kerala had demanded registration of a case against Kodiyeri Balakrishnan for his remark.Vijayan said CPI(M) was not for any political alliance with Congress, which was in tune with the party’s central comittee resolution in this regard at Kolkota. He said the party would move forward by strengthening Left forces in the country.‘The party will organise agitations against BJP’s policies by joining hands with those with whom we can move together,” he said.The Chief Minister alleged that the congress ‘tie up’ with communal forces several times in the past has resulted in the growth of BJP in the country.The saffron party, he alleged,has a record of corruption and was attempting to subvert democracy in the country. “BJP can be opposed only by a right alternative, he said and pointed out that Congressmen were joining BJP en masse.In Tripura, BJP virtually had swallowed Congress, he said and alleged that the saffron party was joining hands with divisive forces. “We must be able to unite all secular and democratic forces to take on the communal outfits. The party has to be strengthened, he said.Meanwhile activists of Hindu Yuva Morcha, the youth wing of BJP, burnt an effigy of the Chief Minister in front of the secretariat in Thiruvananthapuram in protest against his remark and also took out a march in that city. J R Anuraj, District president of the morcha, said they would observe a ‘protest day’ throughout Kerala tomorrow.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T23:42:18+00:00</date><place>Kannur</place></article><article><headline>Mahadayi row: Siddaramaiah says he is open for discussions</headline><description>Manohar Parrikar has still not responded to Karnataka government which had expressed its readiness for talks at "any place and date" to work out an amicable settlement.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Karnataka Chief Minister Siddaramaiah on Saturday said he was still open for discussions with Goa Chief Minister Manohar Parrikar to find an amicable solution to the inter-state Mahadayi river water sharing row.  Meanwhile, state BJP has accused Siddaramaiah of playing politics on the issue by the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T23:19:18+00:00</date><place>Bengaluru</place></article><article><headline>Rahul Gandhi meets President Kovind at Rashtrapati Bhavan</headline><description>"I had a wonderful meeting with President Kovind at the Rashtrapati Bhavan today," Gandhi tweeted.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Congress chief Rahul Gandhi called on President Ram Nath Kovind Saturday, in his first formal meeting after taking over the reins of his party.“I had a wonderful meeting with President Kovind at the Rashtrapati Bhavan today,” Gandhi tweeted.Congress leaders termed it as a courtesy call. In December last year, Rahul Gandhi formally took charge as the president of the Congress party replacing his mother, Sonia Gandhi, who was in office for a record 19 years.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T22:39:11+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Centre-state synergy: JP Nadda, Himachal CM Thakur team-up to woo state cadre deputationists in central govt</headline><description>Nadda assured Thakur his 100 percent backing from the Centre to propose new projects and seek maximum funding in infrastructure, tourism promotion, irrigation and public health and health care projects.</description><author>Ashwani Sharma</author><content>Just on the day when BJP government completed a month in power in Himachal Pradesh, Chief Minister Jai Ram Thakur teamed-up with union health minister J P Nadda on Saturday, holding first-of-its-kind interaction session with all state-cadre officers on the central deputations in Delhi.He sought their help in better centre-state synergy to facilitate new projects funded by the central government as after change of the regime, he wants to push the development agenda faster and take advantage of Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s slogan of “double -engine’ growth in Himachal Pradesh.Thakur led a team of half a dozen key officers from Shimla to Delhi, where Nadda played host to a half-day long interactive session at his official residence to introduce Jai Ram Thakur as state’s new face to lead development initiatives .Nadda assured Thakur his 100 percent backing from the Centre to propose new projects and seek maximum funding in infrastructure, tourism promotion, irrigation and public health and health care projects.The proposals which came under discussions included some of the schemes which the Centre had recently rolled-out for the states but Himachal Pradesh, so far, has not taken advantage of them. These related to expansion of irrigation network, exploitation of minor forest produce for its export-value under the ‘support price’ schemes, proposing projects to newly set-up department of Logistics in the ministry of Commerce, and schemes of under the ministry of heavy industries.Former DGP and now Director General NDRF Sanjay Kumar informed about the proposal to set-up an NDRF centre in Himachal Pradesh.Sanjay Kundu, an IPS officer currently in ministry of irrigation, listed out several schemes which could benefit Himachal Pradesh. An IFS officer wondered why Himachal Pradesh has not explored potential of minor forest produce except wild honey for export.Satwant Atwal, a top ranking woman IPS officer in BSF, also spoke an new initiatives ,where the central establishments can extend help to the state. Few others suggested strengthening of Resident Commissioner’s office in New Delhi by posting more officers.“We have noted down some of the ideas which our officers listed out for action. We will keep a constant touch with the officers in various ministries for a follow-up so that state gets maximum funding “ said Chief Secretary Vineet Chawdharywhen contacted in Delhi.Earlier, Nadda stressed on a good coordination between officers working in the state and Centre. He hailed the officers of Himachal Pradesh for their efficient services.CM Thakur also asked the officers to play pro-active role in speeding up projects and proposals sent by state government to Centre in their respective ministries so that pace of development could be faster.Later in the day, the Himachal CM also met union Home Minister Rajnath Singh and discussed the proposal about setting-up of NDRF battalion in the state which was disaster prone and need to host a centre from where quick help was rushed for the victims.“I also asked Union home Minister to provide funding for police modernisation and raising allowance for Special Protection Officers posted in the border areas with Jammu and Kashmir”, said the CM here.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T22:45:51+00:00</date><place/></article><article><headline>BJD MP Baijayant Panda says he is victim of conspiracy</headline><description>"Had Biju Babu (Naveen Patnaik's father Biju Patnaik) been alive, he would have welcomed my views. People who consider Biju Babu as their ideal would never hesitate to speak truth," Panda said after paying tributes at Biju Patnaik Memorial in Puri.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Suspended BJD MP Baijayant Panda on Saturday said a conspiracy has been hatched against him by a quarter and he is worried that party president Naveen Patnaik could not understand it. Panda said he spoke the truth keeping in mind the interests of the party and that was why action was taken against him. “There was a conspiracy against me since some days. I am worried that my leader (Naveen Patnaik) could not understand the conspiracy,” Panda said.After he was suspended, the MP had talked about a conspiracy hatched against him allegedly by an IAS officer now controlling the party. Stating that he was deeply hurt over the development, Panda said he had never expected to quit the party or create disturbance. The ruling Biju Janata Dal suspended the MP from Kendrapara for alleged anti-party activities on January 24 and on Friday asked to resign from the Lok Sabha on moral and ethical grounds.“Had Biju Babu (Naveen Patnaik’s father Biju Patnaik) been alive, he would have welcomed my views. People who consider Biju Babu as their ideal would never hesitate to speak the truth,” Panda said after paying tributes at Biju Patnaik Memorial in Puri. On his future course of action, Panda said he would decide about it after settling down peacefully. Panda also had darshan of Lord Jagannath at Puri.</content><date>2018-01-27T22:24:14+00:00</date><place>Puri</place></article><article><headline>Andhra Pradesh needs hand-holding due to low per capita income, says N Chandrababu Naidu</headline><description>CM N Chandrababu Naidu, speaking on Saturday, said, "Yes, we have a double digit (economic) growth rate. Our growth is the highest in the country but our per capita income is still low. Extending hand-holding support is the Centre’s responsibility."</description><author>PTI</author><content>Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu on Saturday, without taking names, hit out at NITI Aayog Vice-Chairman Rajiv Kumar over the latter’s comments on the state, saying “some people” are speaking without any understanding of the state’s woes. “Some people are asking why we (AP) need hand-holding when we are registering the highest economic growth. They are speaking without any understanding. This is not correct,” Naidu said at a press conference here this afternoon, without taking any names.During his recent visit to the state, the NITI Aayog Vice-Chairman had made certain observations on AP’s economic growth and had opined that the state “with your 11 per cent and 15 per cent (economic growth rate), you will soon not need any hand-holding.” Kumar had said, “Yes, we will do whatever hand-holding we can. But I am sure, one, that with your 11 per cent and 15 per cent (economic growth), you will soon not need any hand-holding.”Naidu, speaking on Saturday, said, “Yes, we have a double digit (economic) growth rate. Our growth is the highest in the country but our per capita income is still low. Extending hand-holding support is the Centre’s responsibility.” Naidu further said, “Isn’t there a need for the Centre to compensate us (for the financial woes caused by the state’s bifurcation)? That’s what I am asking. Straight question. It is our right. I am very clear on that.”He said they had only been requesting the Centre to “correct” the injustice done to AP on account of bifurcation, adding that he had given all the figures to Prime Minister Narendra Modi during their meeting on January 12. “I explained that despite the highest growth rate, our per capita income is still the lowest. We are Rs 35,000 to Rs 40,000 less than others. I asked him why you will not give us hand-holding support,” Naidu said.The Prime Minister, he added, promised to get everything examined and also personally look into the issue and “correct things”. “We have to wait (for the outcome),” Naidu said. Naidu, responding to a question on the BJP’s demand for appointment of a Governor exclusively for AP, said there was no need for a controversy on it. “It is not correct to speak on some institutions. Some people talk politics but I remain dignified. It is not correct to speak frequently and on the streets about persons holding honourable positions,” he said.BJP state president and MP K Haribabu recently wrote a letter to Union Home Minister Rajnath Singh requesting that an exclusive Governor be appointed for AP in place of E S L Narasimhan, who has been holding charge of both AP and Telangana since June 2, 2014. The BJP’s floor leader in the Assembly P Vishnu Kumar Raju even criticized the Governor for being “biased against AP”.</content><date>2018-01-27T21:56:30+00:00</date><place>Amaravati</place></article><article><headline>Narendra Modi to become first Indian PM to visit Palestine, will travel to UAE and Oman thereafter</headline><description>During the visit, the prime minister will hold discussions on matters of mutual interest with their leaders, apart from participating in other events.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will be on a state visit to Palestine, UAE and Oman from February 9-12. This will be the first-ever visit by an Indian prime minister to Palestine. During the visit, the prime minister will hold discussions on matters of mutual interest with their leaders, apart from participating in other events.PM Modi would be addressing the Sixth World Government Summit being held in Dubai at which India has been extended ‘Guest of Honour’ status. He will also meet the Indian community in UAE and Oman.In Oman, PM Modi’s focus would be on intensifying cooperation in key sectors such as trade and defence. According to the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA), the bilateral trade and investment between India and Oman remain robust and buoyant. Bilateral trade, which saw a decline during 2014-15 and 2015-16, has resumed its upward trend with an increase of 3.6 per cent from USD 3.8 billion in 2015-16 to USD 4 billion in 2016-17, the ministry said.PM Modi’s visit to Palestine assumes huge significance in the sense that India was one of the first countries to recognise the state of Palestine in 1988. The visit to Palestine also comes after PM Modi hosted Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on a six-day visit to India between 14-19 January as the two countries marked the completion of 25 years of the establishment of diplomatic relations.After the Modi-Netanyahu talks, Vijay Gokhale, secretary (economic relations) in the MEA, had said, “What the two sides agreed, that our relationship was much larger than any single issue…that we need to look at it holistically and while we continue to talk to each other, our relationship is not determined by a single issue.” He was asked whether the long-pending issue of Palestine figured in the talks between the two prime ministers.India, however, recently voted for an Arab sponsored resolution that rejected US President Donald Trump’s move to recognise Jerusalem as the Israeli capital despite its close ties with Israel.(With PTI inputs)For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T22:16:20+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Rahul Gandhi approves 70-member campaign committee for Karnataka</headline><description>The committee will have all former union ministers from the state, former PCC presidents, all chiefs of the party's frontal organisations, all AICC office-bearers and all members of both Houses of Parliament as members.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Congress president Rahul Gandhi on Saturday approved a 70-member campaign committee headed by Karnataka Power Minister D K Shivakumar for the coming assembly polls in the southern state, Pradesh Congress Committee (PCC) president G Parmeshwara said. Chief Minister Siddaramaiah will also be a member of the committee which includes all top Congress leaders of the state.Leader of the Congress in Lok Sabha, M Mallikarjun Kharge is also a member of the committee. The committee will have all former union ministers from the state, former PCC presidents, all chiefs of the party’s frontal organisations, all AICC office-bearers and all members of both Houses of Parliament as members.The tenure of the Karnataka Assembly ends in May 2018 and the state is expected to go to polls around April.</content><date>2018-01-27T21:35:45+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Jauhar a form of resistance, not discriminatory practice, says RSS leader</headline><description>The RSS leader also talked on the declining sex-ratio during the seminar, and insisted that women empowerment cannot happen without improving the conditions of women in society. Gopal has previously spoken about untouchability.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Senior RSS leader Krishna Gopal said on Saturday that ‘jauhar’, an ancient practice of mass self-immolation by Rajput women to avoid being captured by foreign invaders, was a form of resistance and not a “discriminatory” practice against women. At a seminar on ‘Stree-Shakti’, or women empowerment, at the Indian Institute of Mass Communication here, Gopal said the practice was “a part of the tradition of Jauhar-Shakha in which women offered the supreme sacrifice than be conquered by victorious armies to be a part of their large harems”. He said jauhar was a “form of resistance and not a discriminatory practice”.The remarks came as fringe Rajput groups violently protested the release of controversial film ‘Padmaavat’, based on the saga of the 13th-century battle between Maharaja Ratan Singh of Mewar and Sultan Alauddin Khilji of Delhi. The groups allege that the film shows Rani Padmavati in “poor light”. The queen is said to have committed ‘jauhar’ in 1303, preferring to die than be captured by Sultan Khilji.Historians, however, are divided whether she actually existed, and the filmmakers have denied the allegations. But Gopal said scholars, who speak about equality between men and women, should consider the fact that the Indian thought was not geared towards dichotomies, but is rather a unifying thought. He said the Indian society must introspect why almost 40 per cent women in the country were bereft of educational opportunities and suffer from debilitating diseases such as anaemia.The RSS leader also talked on the declining sex-ratio during the seminar, and insisted that women empowerment cannot happen without improving the conditions of women in society. Gopal has previously spoken about untouchability. In September last year, he had claimed that the practice of untouchability didn’t exist in ancient India and it reached the country from outside over the past a thousand years.“This (practice of) discrimination came in the last thousand years. There was no such thing as untouchability in this country (before that). “Our Vedic rishis never mentioned this. Where did it come from? It came from outside,” Gopal had told Sangh volunteers during an address in Hyderabad on Vijayadashmi Utsav. Jauhar was a Hindu custom of mass self-immolation by women to avoid capture, enslavement and rape by foreign invaders, when facing a certain defeat in a war.</content><date>2018-01-27T21:13:40+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Natural to have different views, but strive for unity, says PM Modi</headline><description>There are certain proverbs that are often attached to a community or caste but the youth must question and dispel them, PM Modi said.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Saturday said in a democracy it is natural to have different views but one must strive towards unity. Interacting with NCC cadets, NSS volunteers and tableaux artists, he asked them to take responsibility for social change and to fight blind faith.“In order to make India a stronger and progressive nation, then (one should work on) its biggest strength (which) is its unity,” Modi told the young participants. After a photo-opportunity with various groups of young participants, Modi, in a break from tradition, also interacted with the children and addressed them.He told them that in a democracy it is natural to have different views but one must strive towards unity. There are certain proverbs that are often attached to a community or caste but the youth must question and dispel them, Modi said.He also asked them to fight blind faith, starting at home. The prime minister also told the youngsters to take responsibility for social change instead of expecting the government to do everything and urged them to fulfill Mahatma Gandhi’s dream of a clean India by 2019 — the year of the father of the nation’s 150th birth anniversary.Modi told the youngsters that they should make an effort to know more about those who receive civil and military honours, especially those who sacrifice their lives for the country. “Very few people know that in free India 33,000 policemen have sacrificed their lives, which they have for someone’s protection,” Modi said harping on the need to show respect to the police personnel.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T21:09:42+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Jammu &amp; Kashmir CM Mehbooba Mufti speaks to Nirmala Sitharaman after 2 civilians killed in Army firing</headline><description>"The chief minister said every civilian killing, notwithstanding how erroneously made, impairs the political process in the state, which has been put on track after hard work by all political parties," an official spokesman said.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Mehbooba Mufti on Saturday spoke to Defence Minister Nirmala Sitharaman and expressed anguish over the death of two civilians in an Army firing in Shopian district in the state. The two civilians were killed when Army personnel fired on a group of violent protesters, who pelted stones on a security force convoy passing through Ganovpora village.The situation in the village is tense after the deaths. “The chief minister said every civilian killing, notwithstanding how erroneously made, impairs the political process in the state, which has been put on track after hard work by all political parties,” an official spokesman said.Sitharaman assured Mufti she would seek a detailed report in connection with the incident. The defence minister said she would impress upon the field formations that mechanisms put in place were strictly adhered to so that such incidents do not recur, the spokesman said.</content><date>2018-01-27T20:57:38+00:00</date><place>Srinagar</place></article><article><headline>Andhra Pradesh CM cites friendship, refuses to talk on TDP-BJP spats</headline><description>The BJP is part of the Chandrababu government and has two ministers in the Cabinet.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu, refusing to be drawn into a duel with ally BJP, on Saturday said he would speak out if, and when, the latter did not want to continue with the alliance.Naidu was responding to a question on the critical remarks made by some BJP leaders against his government over the last few days.The Telugu Desam Party supremo told a press conference here this afternoon that it was for the BJP leadership to think about the issue. “I will not say anything owing to “mitrapaksha dharmam” (conformity to friendship). Their leadership should think about it,” he said. Naidu added, “I am controlling my people as well and I will continue to control them. I even warned one of our leaders yesterday when he tried to raise the Tadepalligudem issue (related to a dispute between Endowments Minister P Manikyala Rao of the BJP and local TDP leaders).” “If they don’t want an alliance, then we will say namaskar and then talk,” Chandrababu remarked.The BJP is part of the Chandrababu government and has two ministers in the Cabinet. The skirmishes between the allies are nothing new, with both sides hitting out at each other, and Naidu has had to personally intervene to restrain his party colleagues.The BJP’s floor leader in the AP Assembly, Vishnu Kumar Raju, recently found fault with Naidu for inducting four legislators of the opposition YSR Congress, who defected to the TDP, into the state Cabinet. Former Union Minister BJP leader Daggubati Purandeswari, Naidu’s sister-in-law, has also been critical of the state government over several issues, particularly the Polavaram multipurpose project.BJP national executive member and MLC Somu Veerraju said his party would like to strengthen itself in the state and be in a “commanding position” by 2019 elections and not a junior partner to the TDP.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T20:54:58+00:00</date><place>Amaravati</place></article><article><headline>TMC asks why PM Narendra Modi is silent over attack on school bus</headline><description>Protesters allegedly belonging to fringe Rajput group Karni Sena pelted stones at a school bus carrying children shattering its windows. However, no injury was reported on the January 24 incident at Gurugram.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Questioning the silence of Prime Minister Narendra Modi over the attack on school bus by ‘Padmaavat’ protesters, senior Trinamool Congress leader Partha Chatterjee on Saturday said the freedom of speech is under threat under the BJP rule. Protesters allegedly belonging to fringe Rajput group Karni Sena pelted stones at a school bus carrying children shattering its windows. However, no injury was reported on the January 24 incident at Gurugram.“If something happens outside India, the Prime Minister is very fast in tweeting about it. But he is silent when divisive elements are creating a ruckus all over the country,” he said. “We condemn the way the Centre is trying to interfere in our freedom of speech and expression. The freedom of speech is under threat in the BJP rule,” Chatterjee told reporters.</content><date>2018-01-27T20:46:38+00:00</date><place>Kolkata</place></article><article><headline>Centre following appeasement policy for vote bank, says Brinda Karat</headline><description>When Prime Minister Narendra Modi was speaking at World Economic Forum at Davos, "a bus full of school children near our capital at Gurgaon was attacked by Karni Sena which is part of large Sangh Parivar," CPI(M) Polit Bureau member Brinda Karat said.</description><author>PTI</author><content>CPI(M) Polit Bureau member Brinda Karat on Saturday condemned Thursday’s attack on a school bus by anti-Padmaavat protesters in Gurugram and claimed that the BJP led the Centre is following an appeasement policy for vote bank politics. Protesters allegedly belonging to fringe Rajput group Karni Sena pelted stones at a school bus carrying children shattering its windows. However, no injury was reported on the January 24 incident at Gurugram and Karni Sena has denied its involvement in the incident.When Prime Minister Narendra Modi was speaking at the World Economic Forum at Davos, “a bus full of school children near our capital at Gurgaon was attacked by Karni Sena which is part of the large Sangh Parivar,” Karat said. “Neither the Prime Minister nor any of his leaders had anything to say about this. Its clear that the BJP and the RSS are following a policy of appeasement for vote bank politics as far as the Karni Sena is concerned,” she told a press conference.Despite the Supreme Court’s direction to hold shows of Padmaavat, the BJP and RSS ensured that it remained banned as they are supporting those violent actions of those groups, Karat alleged. “I believe this is latest example of intolerance of this government and the Sangh Parivar on freedom of expression,” the senior CPI(M) leader said. On the OXFAM report that said India’s richest 1 per cent now holds a huge 58 per cent of the country’s total wealth, she said the growing inequality in the economic front under the Modi regime is a cause for concern.To a question on the upcoming upcoming Assembly election in Tripura, she said people would re-elect the Left Front giving a befitting reply to the “unholy nexus between the BJP and “the IPFT and huge amount of black money being circulated there by them”. To another question on Himanta Biswa Sarma, who quit the Congress and joined the BJP before the Assembly election in Assam, she said he has now become ‘pavitra’ after bathing in the river of BJP.</content><date>2018-01-27T20:16:34+00:00</date><place>Guwahati</place></article><article><headline>Thirty-eight held for anti-‘Padmaavat’ violence in Gurgaon: Police</headline><description>The national secretary of Karni Sena, Suraj Pal Amu, was arrested on Friday on charges of breaching peace in the city. He has been sent into judicial custody until Monday.</description><author>PTI</author><content>At least 38 people have been arrested or detained in connection with the violence by fringe Rajput groups against the screening of Sanjay Leela Bhansali’s controversial film ‘Padmaavat’ in Gurgaon, police said on Saturday. Gurgaon Police PRO Ravinder Kumar told PTI that the department arrested 24 people for their alleged involvement in violent incidents, and another 14 as part of preventive measures under Section 107/151 of the CrPC, in eight cases.He dismissed social media reports that Muslim youths were detained or arrested, and urged people to not pay attention to rumours, but follow the district administration’s guidelines. Kumar said the people arrested have been sent to judicial custody by a court. On Wednesday, a school bus carrying 20-25 students was targeted in Gurgaon and the Delhi-Jaipur national highway was blocked by supporters of Karni Sena, which is at the forefront of the opposition to the film, and other Rajput fringe groups.Another state-run bus was torched near Bhondsi village. The protesters allege that the movie based on the saga of the 13th-century battle between Maharaja Ratan Singh of Mewar and Sultan Alauddin Khilji of Delhi, distorts history and shows Rani Padmavati in “poor light”, despite historians being divided on whether the queen actually existed. The filmmakers, too, have denied the allegations.The groups nonetheless had threatened the owners of more than 40 multiplexes and theatres operating in Gurgaon to not screen the film. Fearing trouble in the area, the police had on Tuesday imposed prohibitory orders. But the protesters still rampaged through, forcing residents to initially avoid theatres. On Saturday, the police said the situation was under control.“Best efforts are being made by police teams to identify other miscreants involved in previous violent incidents which occurred in different places in the district,” Kumar said. He said a special investigation team, headed by a DCP-rank officer, has been formed to probe the incidents. The SIT will strive to collect scientific evidences and identify the remaining people involved in the violence, he added.“The situation in Gurgaon is peaceful. Police personnel have been deployed in large numbers at malls, multiplexes and sensitive locations to maintain law and order,” Kumar said. The national secretary of Karni Sena, Suraj Pal Amu, was arrested on Friday on charges of breaching peace in the city. He has been sent into judicial custody until Monday.</content><date>2018-01-27T20:07:52+00:00</date><place>Gurgaon</place></article><article><headline>‘Sleeze talk’ case: Former Kerala minister acquitted of sexual harassment charges</headline><description>The case was registered against Saseendran after the woman filed a complaint, in which she stated that he had misbehaved with her when she met him for an interview at his office. Saseendran resigned as minister in March 2017 and Thomas Chandy, the other MLA of the party, replaced him as the transport minister.</description><author>PTI</author><content>A local court in Thiruvananthapuram on Saturday acquitted NCP MLA and former Kerala transport minister A K Saseendran of the sexual harassment charges levelled by a woman journalist.With the chief judicial magistrate’s court here acquitting him, the way has been cleared for Saseendran’s re-induction into the CPI(M)-led government headed by Chief Minister Pinarayi Vijayan.The court acquitted Saseendran holding that no case had been made out against him that warranted conviction. The case, an off-shoot of a sleaze audio tape row involving Saseendran and the woman, had taken a new turn with the latter reversing her statement in court that he had misbehaved with her.She had also stated during cross examination that she was not sure about whether the “person on the other side of the phone” was Saseendran. In a related development in the case, a public interest litigation was filed in the court this morning stating that the woman journalist might have reversed her statement due to “fear” and that the proceedings should not be closed.The chief judicial magistrate rejected the plea, stating that it was a matter between the two persons and a third person cannot interfere into it. Mystery also surrounded the PIL as there were reports that the address of the petitioner given in the plea was not correct.The case was registered against Saseendran after the woman filed a complaint, in which she stated that he had misbehaved with her when she met him for an interview at his office. Saseendran resigned as minister in March 2017 and Thomas Chandy, the other MLA of the party, replaced him as the transport minister.However, Chandy also had to resign in November 2017 after allegations of land encroachment surfaced against him. The NCP state leadership had then taken a decision that whoever comes clean of charges first would become the minister again.Expressing happiness over the verdict, Saseendran said he would abide by the party leadership’s decision. Saseendran ran into trouble after a Malayalam TV channel aired a purported sleaze audio of him in conversation with a woman, who was later identified as the petitioner journalist.The channel had later tendered an apology admitting that it had conducted a “sting operation” involving one of its women journalists and not a housewife, as claimed earlier. The Justice P S Antony commission, which went into the allegations against the former minister, had in its report submitted to the government in November last year stated that it could not ascertain the authenticity of the purported voice clip of Saseendran.The CEO of the channel and four mediapersons were arrested in connection with ‘sleaze audio’ case and were now out on bail.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T19:57:22+00:00</date><place>Thiruvananthapuram</place></article><article><headline>‘Aadhaar’ is Oxford dictionary’s Hindi word of 2017</headline><description>Other words such as 'Mitron', 'Notebandi', 'Gau-Rakshak' were also considered, but the widespread discussions and debates around 'Aadhaar' was the reason it was selected as the word of the year</description><author>PTI</author><content>Oxford Dictionaries has chosen ‘Aadhaar’ as the Hindi word of 2017. The word gained popularity due to Aadhaar card, which was in news last year and is likely to remain in highlight this year as well. The announcement was made at a session “Oxford Dictionaries’ Hindi Word of the Year” during the ongoing Jaipur Literature Festival here.Other words such as ‘Mitron’, ‘Notebandi’, ‘Gau-Rakshak’ were also considered, but the widespread discussions and debates around ‘Aadhaar’ was the reason it was selected as the word of the year, journalist Saurabh Dwivedi said during the discussion.Writer Pankaj Dubey said new words like ‘Sleepawastha’ (state of sleeping), ‘Maukatarian’ (opportunist) should be coined to express certain moods. Chitra Mudgal objected to the suggestion and instead advocated for the correct use of languages.“If a person with lack of proper knowledge coins and expresses such words then it can be understood but this is not acceptable when educated people do this,” Mudgal, an author, said.Poet and writer Ashok Vajpeyi said politicians use Hindi word ‘Mitron’ (friends) which is not grammatically correct, when in fact the correct word is ‘Mitro’ — an apparent reference to Prime Minister Narendra Modi who uses the term often in his speeches. Vajpeyi said the responsibility to conserve language lies with people.“Changes would come, new words would be coined but ultimately the responsibility to conserve the language is on citizens,” he said.Talking about the languages used by media, journalist Vinod Dua said that media’s job is to provide news in a simple language for the audience, instead of creating a literature while broadcasting the news.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T21:32:06+00:00</date><place>Jaipur</place></article><article><headline>Office-of-profit case: CM Arvind Kejriwal reschedules Nagpur visit</headline><description>At the insistence of Union Surface Transport and Shipping Minister Nitin Gadkari, Kejriwal was to embark on a two-day Nagpur visit on Saturday. Official also said that new dates of CM's visit to Nagpur, a home town of Gadkari, will be announced soon.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal has rescheduled his two-day visit to Nagpur in view of Transport Minister Kailash Gahlot being “busy with the preparations” for the office-of-profit case in the Delhi High Court on Monday. An official said that Gahlot was also to accompany the chief minister during his visit to see development projects initiated by BJP-ruled Nagpur Municipal Corporation (NMC).The day-to-day hearing will start in the Delhi High Court in the disqualification case of 20 AAP MLAs for allegedly holding office-of-profit as parliamentary secretaries from Monday, the official said. Gahlot is among the 20 Aam Aadmi Party MLAs who have been disqualified by the president on the recommendation of the Election Commission. The party has challenged the decision in the high court.“As the transport minister is busy with preparations of office-of-profit case, the chief minister’s Nagpur visit has been rescheduled,” the official.At the insistence of Union Surface Transport and Shipping Minister Nitin Gadkari, Kejriwal was to embark on a two-day Nagpur visit on Saturday. Official also said that the new dates of chief minister’s visit to Nagpur, a home town of Gadkari, will be announced soon.</content><date>2018-01-27T19:36:45+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Breaking stereotypes: Woman Imam leads Friday prayer service in Kerala’s Malappuram district</headline><description>Jamitha, known as 'Jamitha teacher' among her fellow people, said the Holy Quran never discriminates between men and women and Islam never stops women from being 'imams'.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Breaking gender stereotypes, a 34-year-old woman has led Jumu’ah, a Friday prayer service of Muslims, here in Kerala, claimed to be the first in the history of the country. Jamitha, the general secretary of Quran Sunnat Society, took the role of the ‘imam’ of the prayers held at the office of the Society in the Muslim-dominated district yesterday. Jumu’ah, the congregational prayer held every Friday, is usually led by men. Around 80 people, including women, gathered to attend the prayers, led by the woman ‘Imam’, the Society sources said.Jamitha, known as ‘Jamitha teacher’ among her fellow people, said the Holy Quran never discriminates between men and women and Islam never stops women from being ‘imams’.“It is for the first time that a woman is leading Jumu’ah in the history of our country. It was held at the central committee office of our Society, where we used to gather every Friday for the prayers,” she told PTI.It was not mandatory for the Jumu’ah to be held only at mosques, she said. Hailing from Thiruvananthapuram, Jamitha also said she would continue to lead the prayer service on Fridays. The radical move has kicked up a wide debate for and against the practise of a woman leading Jumu’ah, on the social media.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T19:30:03+00:00</date><place>Kerala</place></article><article><headline>Maharashtra sees 85 leopard deaths in 2017, six less than 2016</headline><description>Natural causes accounted for the highest number of deaths at 55 while accidents claimed the lives of 21 leopards.</description><author>PTI</author><content>As many as 85 leopards have died in Maharashtra due to various causes, including poaching, during 2017, a state forest official told PTI.He added that Nashik saw the highest number of leopard deaths at 20 followed by Kolhapur with 13 deaths. Natural causes accounted for the highest number of deaths at 55 while accidents claimed the lives of 21 leopards.Nine leopards were also hunted, he said. The official was quoting figures from the data compiled by the statistics department. He, however, added that the number of deaths for 2017 was six less than the toll for 2016.“Electrocution, getting run over while crossing roads, drowning in wells and old age are the four primary reasons for these deaths. Of these, the first three are man-made causes,” the data revealed.Rohan Bhate, honorary wildlife warden from Satara explained, “The leopard is a territorial animal and survives by hunting small animals like hare, deer, goat and sheep. Increasing human intervention in the fringes of forests has affected the prey base of the leopards. This, in turn, has forced them to move towards towns and human settlements.”“The human intervention includes construction of roads and water canals, and erection of high tension electricity cables,” explained Raman Kulkarni, honorary wild life warden from Kolhapur.Data from the forest department show that 350 leopards have died in the state since 2013.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T19:09:24+00:00</date><place>Mumbai</place></article><article><headline>DMK warns of intensifying stir against bus fare hike in Tamil Nadu</headline><description>M Karunanidhi would decline their plea saying state-run transport corporations were not meant to make profit and that any losses should be borne keeping in mind the interests of the people, DMK working president M K Stalin said.</description><author>PTI</author><content>The DMK on Saturday staged state-wide agitations against the recent hike in bus fares effected by the AIADMK government in Tamil Nadu and warned of intensifying its protests if the revision was not rolled back immediately. DMK working president and Leader of Opposition in Tamil Nadu Assembly, M K Stalin, demanded that Chief Minister K Palaniswami should immediately withdraw the hike or resign.“The chief minister had said the hike was effected with anguish. If indeed so, it should be immediately withdrawn. Else, you (Palaniswami) have got no option left other than to resign,” Stalin said. He said his party would wait for a couple of days to see whether the state government acted on their plea, else would start staging protests without permission.In other words, it would be a ‘jail bharo’ agitation, he said. Stalin said the January 19 increase in bus fares had come as a “jolt” to the ordinary people, adding many of them such as daily wage labourers were now forced to spend a large part of their earnings towards commuting in buses. “I had written to the chief minister four days back, asking him to withdraw the hike, and that the matter should be discussed in the state assembly for which the House should be convened. But they are only giving accounts of losses (suffered by transport corporations) but have no time for remedial measures,” he said.The DMK has, therefore, constituted a panel under senior party leader and former Union minister T R Baalu to probe ways to reduce bus fares, Stalin said. He recalled that during the DMK rule of 2006-11, his father and then chief minister M Karunanidhi had never effected such a hike, despite repeated pleas from officials of the transport department.Karunanidhi would decline their plea saying state-run transport corporations were not meant to make profit and that any losses should be borne keeping in mind the interests of the people, Stalin said. After a hiatus of six years, the AIADMK government had on January 19 hiked ticket fares of buses operated by state-run transport corporations and private entities by about 20 to 54.54 per cent, drawing flak from civil society and political parties alike.</content><date>2018-01-27T19:02:42+00:00</date><place>Chennai</place></article><article><headline>Don’t allow parliamentary secretaries in Gujarat: Congress to governor</headline><description>The Supreme Court, in its July 26, 2017 order, had held that a state government has no right to appoint a parliamentary secretary, Gohil said.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Senior Congress leader Shaktisinh Gohil on Saturday wrote to Gujarat Governor O P Kohli, saying he shouldn’t allow the BJP government in the state to appoint Parliamentary Secretaries. Gohil claimed that Chief Minister Vijay Rupani was planning to appoint parliamentary secretaries to appease some disgruntled BJP MLAs who could not find place in the ministry.The governor must not give his assent for these appointments as the post is unconstitutional and it will amount to a contempt of court, the Congress leader said. The Supreme Court, in its July 26, 2017 order, had held that a state government has no right to appoint a parliamentary secretary, Gohil said.“To contain dissatisfaction in his party, the chief minister, despite being aware of the Supreme Court’s order, is talking about appointing a number of parliamentary secretaries which is against Constitution and will amount to a contempt of court,” the Congress leader said.Past BJP governments in Gujarat appointed parliamentary secretaries to favour party MLAs, he said. “It is learnt that the BJP is going to appoint parliamentary secretaries to manage growing dissent in the party,” Gohil claimed.The issue of legal status of parliamentary secretaries came to the fore recently when President Ram Nath Kovind approved disqualification of 20 AAP MLAs in Delhi upon the recommendation by the Election Commission. The EC said the post of parliamentary secretary which they held was an ‘office of profit’.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T18:34:41+00:00</date><place>Ahmedabad</place></article><article><headline>India condemns ‘barbaric and dastardly’ terrorist attack in Kabul, offers all possible assistance</headline><description>In a statement, the ministry of external affairs said, "India strongly condemns the barbaric and dastardly terrorist attacks in Kabul today that targeted innocent civilians and the wounded under treatment."</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Condemning the “barbaric and dastardly” terrorist attacks in Kabul in which 95 people lost their lives and over 150 got injured, India on Saturday said that it stands in solidarity with the government and people of Afghanistan and that it will offer all possible assistance to the country.In a statement, the Ministry of External Affairs said, “India strongly condemns the barbaric and dastardly terrorist attacks in Kabul today that targeted innocent civilians and the wounded under treatment. This follows the cowardly terror attack on the children and civilians in Jalalabad on 24 January.”The ministry further said that there could be no justification for such reprehensible attacks. “The perpetrators of these attacks and their supporters should be brought to justice.”While offering condolences to the next of kins of victims of these terror attacks, the statement added that India stands ready to extend all possible assistance, including for treatment of those injured.President Kovind also condemned the attacks and offered his condolence. “Shocked at news of the terrorist attack in Kabul. Our thoughts are with the bereaved families and with those injured. India stands shoulder-to-shoulder with the people and government of Afghanistan in the fight against the forces of terror and evil,” he tweeted.The International Committee of the Red Cross also condemned the attack in a tweet, saying,”The use of an ambulance in today’s attack in (hash)Kabul is harrowing. This could amount to perfidy under IHL. Unacceptable and unjustifiable.”The incident took place on Saturday afternoon after an ambulance packed with explosives blew up in a crowded area near a police checkpoint close to foreign embassies and official government buildings on Saturday, Reuters reported. The Taliban has claimed responsibility for the attack.Zabihullah Mujahid, a Taliban spokesman, claimed responsibility for the bombing, which sent thick, black smoke into the sky from the site near the government’s former Interior Ministry building. Also nearby are the European Union and Indian consulates.  READ MORE The blast – one of the biggest since a truck bomb ripped through the Afghan capital’s diplomatic quarter on May 31 last year – led to chaotic scenes as panic-stricken people fled the area where several high-profile organisations, including the European Union, have offices.Earlier this week on Tuesday, a raid by the Taliban on a high-end hotel had killed at least 20 people, including 13 foreigners. In another attack on the Afghan soil, an office of the Save the Children aid agency in Jalalabad had been targetted by militants wounding 11 people, reported Reuters quoting local sources.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T21:15:16+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article><article><headline>Classmates slapped girl 168 times on teacher’s direction: Father</headline><description>The incident took place at the Navodaya Vidyalaya in Thandla town and the girl's father, Shivpratap Singh, told police that she was slapped 168 times between January 11 -16 for not completing her homework.</description><author>PTI</author><content>A 12-year-old girl was slapped 168 times over a period of six days by her classmates at a residential school on the instructions of their teacher, the child’s father complained to school authorities and police. However, the school principal K Sagar termed it a “friendly” punishment.“They were not strong slaps but mild and friendly ones. We will also talk to the parents,” Sagar said.The incident took place at the Navodaya Vidyalaya in Thandla town and the girl’s father, Shivpratap Singh, told police that she was slapped 168 times between January 11 -16 for not completing her homework. The girl is a student of Class VI at the school.He told police that the school’s science teacher, Manoj Kumar Verma, on January 11, told his daughter’s classmates to slap her as a form of punishment and 14 girls slapped her two times every day for six days.Singh also stated in his complaint, filed a couple of days ago, that his child was unwell and therefore was unable to complete her homework. He alleged that the school was aware of his child’s illness. He also told police that his daughter fell ill due to fear and distress and refused to go to school, following which she had to be admitted to a local hospital.Thandla police station in-charge S S Baghel confirmed that a complaint had been received but added that no injury was found during medical examination conducted on the girl.“We had received a complaint. No injury was found during the medical examination of the girl. Our team also visited the school and found that such an incident had occurred. We are investigating further. However, no formal case has been registered so far,” he said.School Principal Sagar defended the action of the teacher and termed the disciplining method a “friendly” punishment.“We don’t allow corporal punishment in the school. The girl is weak in studies and doesn’t complete her assignments,” he said, adding that the teacher chose this form punishment to improve her performance in school.District Collector Ashish Saxena said that the issue had come to his knowledge and he had ordered an investigation.For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T18:17:53+00:00</date><place>Jhabua</place></article><article><headline>Assembly polls: Congress releases list of 57 candidates in Meghalaya, 56 in Tripura</headline><description>Polling in Tripura will take place on February 18, while Meghalaya will vote on February 27. The counting of votes in both the states will be held on March 3.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>The Congress Party on Saturday released the list of its candidates for the forthcoming assembly polls in Meghalaya and Tripura. The party has fielded 56 candidates in Tripura, while in Meghalaya 57 candidates will be trying their luck.INC COMMUNIQUEAnnouncement of the list of Congress candidates for the ensuing elections to the Legislative Assembly of Tripura. pic.twitter.com/f7XgP0Khn7— INC Sandesh (@INCSandesh) January 27, 2018Polling in Tripura will take place on February 18, while Meghalaya goes to polls on February 27. The counting of votes in both the states will be held on March 3. Meghalaya chief minister Mukul Sangma will contest from two seats in the state.INC COMMUNIQUEAnnouncement of the list of Congress candidates for the ensuing elections to the Legislative Assembly of Meghalaya. pic.twitter.com/oUgcft3Eaa— INC Sandesh (@INCSandesh) January 27, 2018The tenure of the current 60-member assemblies in both Meghalaya and Tripura ends on March 6 and March 14, respectively.Meanwhile, Congress president Rahul Gandhi is scheduled to arrive in Shillong on January 30 for a two-day meeting with the party workers and supporters of the poll-bound state.The Congress had faced a major setback earlier this month when five of its MLAs resigned from the assembly and joined the NPP, and two other legislators moved to the BJP and the newly formed People’s Democratic Front.The BJP, on the other hand, has said that it is in the process of finalising the visit of its star campaigners which include Prime Minister Narendra Modi. PM Modi had visited the state last month and addressed a gathering at Polo Grounds in Shillong. The rally was attended by thousands of people, including the BJP workers.(With PTI inputs)For all the latest India News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-01-27T18:06:10+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place></article>
	</current_affairs>























<sports><article><headline>&#8216;Copy Paste&#8217;: BCCI letter gaffe leaves associations&#160;confused</headline><description>The BCCI was left red-faced after a letter it sent to state associations on the upcoming annual domestic captain-coaches' conclave, to be held in Mumbai on February 28, carried a glaring error.</description><author>PTI</author><content>The BCCI was on Tuesday left red-faced after a letter it sent to state associations on the upcoming annual domestic captain-coaches&#8217; conclave, to be held in Mumbai on February 28, carried a glaring error.The letter sent to state associations by BCCI acting secretary Amitabh Chaudhary, a copy of which is in possession of PTI, states that the &#8220;purpose of meeting is to seek feedback from the captains and coaches about Ranji Trophy season 2016-17 and discuss the same&#8221;.What left a lot of state associations confused was the &#8220;2016-17 season&#8221; in place of what should have been 2017-18 season.While it is clear that it was a factual-cum-typographical error committed by the administrative department, what baffled many state unit officials was that nobody bothered to send a corrected version till today evening.&#8220;It may have been an error on their part but it looked like a copy-paste job taking the template out of an earlier year&#8217;s letter. They should be a bit more careful about it,&#8221; a senior state board functionary told PTI on conditions of anonymity.He added, &#8220;I believe the secretary (Chaudhary) should at least read before signing any document. It reflects BCCI in poor light and also shows the seriousness about domestic events.&#8221;The meeting has been called a day after the Vijay Hazare Trophy to make it more meaningful as the chairman of selectors, MSK Prasad, will also be present and give his inputs regarding the scheduling of tournaments, which will help in smooth selection of senior and A teams.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T20:30:31+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>I-League: East Bengal hand Minerva Punjab first defeat at home, title race heats&#160;up</headline><description>East Bengal handed leaders Minerva Punjab FC their first defeat at home this season to stay alive in the I-League title race with a crucial 1-0 win in Panchkula on Tuesday.</description><author>PTI</author><content>East Bengal handed leaders Minerva Punjab FC their first defeat at home this season to stay alive in the I-League title race with a crucial 1-0 win in Panchkula on Tuesday.Third-placed East Bengal&#8217;s win was made possible owing to a thunderous long-range volley from Cavin Lobo on the hour mark at the Tau Devi Lal Stadium.Apart from the early few minutes, East Bengal dominated the game having penetrated Minerva&#8217;s defence with sharp through balls from the flanks.Minerva Punjab&#8217;s goalkeeper Rakshit had to come out of his position numerous times to clear the ball from one-on-one situation to keep the scoreline unscathed.Minerva slowly came back into the game in the latter part of the first half when Chencho and William started attacking from both wings. The Red &amp; Golds almost conceded an own goal from a wayward clearance by Eduardo in the 37th minute, which landed on the roof of the net.Meanwhile, East Bengal missed an easy chance to go forward when Yami Longvah failed to connect a cross inside the box in the 35th minute, resulting in an early change by Khalid Jamil, who introduced Ghenafo Kromah at his expense.At half time, it was even-stevens as both teams tried adjusting to the ground conditions.Minerva started the second half sharply with pacey attacks from wings. Gagandeep had an outrageous opportunity in the 48th minute but his mistimed shot was easily stopped by Ubaid.Minerva then had another chance when William was tripped in a dangerous position just outside the penalty box but the resultant free kick by Sukhdev was off-target.But an absolute stunner by Lobo silenced the home crowd to give his side the lead with 30 minutes of game-time left.Chencho had an extremely good chance to level the score in the 79th minute but his shot went straight into the goalie&#8217;s gloves.Chencho made an excellent run straight into the opposition&#8217;s box beating three players in the process and eventually, delivered a delicious cross to William who had ample time to hit the target, but his wayward header missed it.The visitors then held on their nerves for the remaining minutes to get three crucial points and stay alive in the title race.The Kolkata giants will now travel to Kozhikode to challenge Gokulam Kerala FC on February 17, while Minerva Punjab FC will host the Kerala-based side three days later.Minerva Punjab have 29 points from 14 games, second-placed Neroca FC have 28 from 15 matches, while East Bengal have 26 points from 14.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T20:17:50+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Jose Mourinho backs VAR technology amid mixed&#160;response</headline><description>Jose Mourinho supports the use of the video assistant referee (VAR) system despite the mixed response it has generated since its debut in English football in the FA Cup last month.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Manchester United manager Jose Mourinho supports the use of the video assistant referee (VAR) system despite the mixed response it has generated since its debut in English football in the FA Cup last month.United play their first match with VAR when they travel to Huddersfield Town for their FA Cup fifth round clash on Saturday and Mourinho stressed that the technology had to be embraced, although it needed to iron out some issues.&#8220;Of course they (VAR) need adjustments,&#8221; Mourinho told the club&#8217;s website (www.manutd.com).&#8220;They need to make sure they don&#8217;t change the dynamic of the game too much, the emotion of the game too much &#8211; people waiting a couple of minutes to know if they can jump (and celebrate) because it was a goal. But from my professional perspective, I like the feeling of a right decision coming. It&#8217;s a penalty or not a penalty, it&#8217;s handball or not handball, it&#8217;s a red card or not a red card. I think a fair decision is a feeling that I like.&#8221;The technology is also being trialled around the world, however critics have pointed out the length of the reviews while some supporters in the stadium are unhappy at being left in the dark about replays that TV viewers can watch over again.English clubs are not alone in experiencing teething trouble related to the use of the system, with VAR decisions seemingly only adding to the confusion rather than stopping it in Italy&#8217;s Seria A.VAR induced more controversy on Monday when the Portuguese football federation (FPF) said it had been wrongly used to disallow a goal at the weekend.Backing the referees, Mourinho added: &#8220;They want to perform the best they can, they don&#8217;t like to make mistakes&#8230; so if the referees are happy with technological support, then yes, let&#8217;s go for the VAR.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T19:55:39+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Fed Cup performance very encouraging , says Sania&#160;Mirza</headline><description>Sania Mirza feels Ankita Raina's performance in the recent Fed Cup was encouraging but the team must progress to the next level.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Indian tennis ace Sania Mirza feels Ankita Raina&#8217;s performance in the recent Fed Cup was encouraging but the team must progress to the next level.&#8220;We have always come back empty-handed. We see great progress in young talent but never make the next jump. That is something we are totally missing,&#8221; said Sania here today.Ankita was the standout performer for India in the Fed Cup, notching up victories over higher-ranked opponents even though the team lost the opportunity to progress after successive defeats. The country, however, managed to stay in the Asia/Oceania Group 1 with a 2-0 win over Chinese Taipei in the relegation play-off.&#8220;It is very encouraging to see Ankita have those couple of wins against the top 100 players. Even though they came out on the losing end of the tie, you still have to take the small positive out,&#8221; she added.Asked who has the potential to be the next Sania, the 31-year-old said she should not be the benchmark for upcoming talent.&#8220;I have been asked about who is the next Sania for many many years and I have always said why next Sania? We should try to aim better than Sania. Why just me?&#8221;Sania, whose doubles ranking has dipped to 14th due to the ongoing injury lay-off, feels persistence is the key to success and the young generation must keep working hard.Winner of six Grand Slam titles, Sania, has been out of action since October 2017 due to an injury in her right knee but is hopeful of a French Open comeback.&#8220;I don&#8217;t really have a time frame (for recovery) right now, I cannot put a date to it. Every day is a battle for me. But French Open is in May end, hopefully I will be back by then,&#8221; she said.Asked about the return of stalwarts like Serena Williams and Maria Sharapova to the circuit, Sania said women&#8217;s tennis has unbelievable depth.&#8220;Women&#8217;s tennis has never been anybody&#8217;s monopoly besides Serena. Apart from her, it was always sort of anyone. It was only when Serena loses that it becomes wide open,&#8221; she said.&#8220;Women&#8217;s tennis has unbelievable depth and therefore you see many lower-ranked players defeating a world No 5 or a No 2. Serena will be back and I think she&#8217;s the greatest tennis player we have ever had,&#8221; Sania added.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T19:45:13+00:00</date><category>tennis</category></article><article><headline>Breaks, lighter schedules can help players improve, says Roger&#160;Federer</headline><description>Roger Federer believes he has benefited from a lighter schedule and says players should not be afraid of taking breaks from tennis to improve their game.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Swiss ace Roger Federer believes he has benefited from a lighter schedule and says players should not be afraid of taking breaks from tennis to improve their game.The 36-year-old was sidelined for a significant period in 2016 with a knee injury and upon his return in 2017, Federer competed in just 12 tournaments and the move appears to have paid off.Federer, who stormed to his 20th major title at the Australian Open last month, says he understands the demands of the sport after playing a full schedule for over 15 years and believes that players can improve from intervals.&#8220;You can always play more if you want to,&#8221; Federer told the Guardian newspaper.&#8220;You can always play less if you want to. I just hope people don&#8217;t think that what I&#8217;m doing at 36 they can start doing at 25. I played full schedule from 1998 or 1999 to 2016. Until I was injured,&#8221; .&#8220;My philosophy is I play when I&#8217;m ready&#8230; What I did last year &#8211; and what Rafa (Nadal) is doing also &#8211; is maybe a bit of a lighter schedule, and it shows to others by working or practising a bit more&#8230; you become a different or better player.&#8221;World number one Nadal, who evenly split the four grand slam titles with Federer last season, also had a similar lay-off in 2016 with a wrist problem and came back stronger to take his major title tally to 16.&#8220;Say I go out for six months and I only work on my serve-and-volley game. I feel like I&#8217;d be a different player six months later but everybody&#8217;s scared to do it&#8230;,&#8221; Federer added.&#8220;I hope I take that fear away a little bit, that sometimes it&#8217;s OK to take time. That would be a wish for me: that players would read something into that &#8211; not that they just start doing it because the top guys are doing it. We&#8217;re doing it because we&#8217;re older and we have thousands of matches in our bodies. That&#8217;s why we have to do it this way.&#8221;Federer is set to play Belgian Ruben Bemelmans in the opening round of the ABN Amro World Tennis event in Rotterdam on Wednesday and is in contention to reclaim the top spot in rankings.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T19:24:41+00:00</date><category>tennis</category></article><article><headline>Rohit Sharma slams 17th ODI hundred in Port&#160;Elizabeth</headline><description>Rohit Sharma made amends to his disastrous tour of South Africa by slamming his 17th ODI hundred at St George's Park on Tuesday.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Rohit Sharma finally made amends to his disastrous tour of South Africa by slamming his 17th ODI hundred in Port Elizabeth on Tuesday. With 40 runs in four matches so far and a miserable average of 10 in the ODI series, Rohit Sharma has had a tour to forget and was under scrutiny for his poor performance. But, he roared back to form with a stunning century at St George&#8217;s Park and reached the three-figure mark with a quick two at backward square leg at off Tabraiz Shamsi. This was Sharma&#8217;s first at this ground and only the second against South Africa. Sharma was finally dismissed for 115 (126 balls) by&#160;Lungi Ngidi.His hundred which came off 107 balls and was laced with 10 fours, four huge sixes. Having failed to register a single fifty in eight innings now, Sharma was desperately in need for such an innings. However, he did survive a couple of scares before reaching the magic figure of 100. A couple of close run-out chances, a DRS review which was turned down and a drop by Shamsi on 96 saw the Mumbaikar survive score a fine century. After Sachin, Tendulkar, Virat Kohli, Sourav Ganguly, Sharma is now fourth on the list of most number of ODI hundreds for India.A great innings under pressure!! Congratulations on your 17th ODI &#128175;, @ImRo45. Time for some fireworks &#128293; now &#128526; #TeamIndia #SAvIND pic.twitter.com/Nqyik8lj2N&#8212; Suresh Raina (@ImRaina) 13 February 2018Earlier, Sharma began his innings cautiously and scored his first run after 15 deliveries. He also had to clear the Rabada hurdle at the start as six out of his eight dismissals have come against South Africa&#8217;s young pace spearhead. But once he settled down there was no looking back.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T19:31:30+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>Winter Olympics 2018: No official complaints about high winds, says&#160;FIS</headline><description>FIS has refuted claims that athletes' complaints had been ignored in the build-up to the controversial women's snowboard slopestyle Olympic final on Monday.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>The International Ski Federation (FIS) has refuted claims that athletes&#8217; complaints had been ignored in the build-up to the controversial women&#8217;s snowboard slopestyle Olympic final on Monday.Several athletes, including Austrian Anna Gasser and Norway&#8217;s Silje Norendal, complained after the final that the extreme wind and hard snow made conditions too dangerous to compete and said they had requested the event be postponed.The start of the final was delayed by more than an hour because of the wind, but after qualification was cancelled entirely on Sunday due to the weather, organisers decided it could go ahead.Only five of the 25 riders competing made it down the first run without falling in the difficult conditions and none of them completed two error-free runs.American Jamie Anderson coped best and retained her title with a score of 83.00 points at the Phoenix Snow Park.FIS communications manger Jenny Wiedeke said on Tuesday that only one team had made a complaint before the final.&#8220;FIS has a very clear line of communication with its athletes and coaches,&#8221; she told Reuters.&#8220;We do have connection coaches and athlete representatives for our events and especially in snowboard freestyle because it&#8217;s a smaller field the athletes have much more direct contact with our directors.It wasn&#8217;t a protest which one team issued, they just went to our race director Roby (Moresi) and just voiced their concerns about the wind conditions, so there was no formal protest.&#8221;The weather was much improved at the venue on Tuesday, with the women&#8217;s snowboard halfpipe final going ahead without any problems.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T19:06:11+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Argentina want Lionel Messi to play less for Barcelona, says president Claudio&#160;Tapia</headline><description>AFA President Claudio Tapia has said he has spoken to captain Lionel Messi about playing fewer games for La Liga side Barcelona in order to stay fresh for his country ahead of the 2018 World Cup.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Argentina&#8217;s national football association (AFA) president Claudio Tapia has said he has spoken to captain Lionel Messi about playing fewer games for La Liga side Barcelona in order to stay fresh for his country ahead of the 2018 World Cup.Tapia&#8217;s pleas have largely gone unheeded by Barca coach Ernesto Valverde, who has started Messi in 33 of the team&#8217;s total 39 games this season, only leaving him out of the matchday squad in three King&#8217;s Cup games.The coach did leave Messi out of the starting line-up for the first time in the league against Espanyol on Feb. 4 but threw the Argentine on as a substitute to help salvage a 1-1 draw.&#8220;I hope all the players arrive in the level they are at the moment. Sergio Aguero is playing outstanding right now and Lionel Messi is always at the top of his game,&#8221; Tapia told Argentine network TYC Sports.&#8220;That&#8217;s vital for the directors and the coaching staff. We have spoken to Messi about taking care of himself and about playing less for Barcelona.&#8221;Tapia also said Argentina are planning to play a friendly against Catalonia in June as part of their preparations for the World Cup in Russia, where they will hope to better their runners-up finish four years ago in Brazil.A game against Catalonia could theoretically see Messi come up against Barca team mates Sergio Busquets, Sergi Roberto and Gerard Pique among others. However, such a fixture could prove controversial in Spain after increased tensions between the central government and the region over its independence drive.&#8220;(Argentina coach) Jorge (Sampaoli) told me it would be good for us from a football point of view and it&#8217;s important for us from a financial point of view, but we haven&#8217;t closed the deal yet,&#8221; added Tapia.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T18:53:51+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Dipa Karmakar ruled out of Commonwealth&#160;Games</headline><description>Dipa Karmakar has been forced out of the upcoming Commonwealth Games owing to the career-threatening knee injury she picked up last year, her coach Bisweshwar Nandi said on Tuesday.</description><author>PTI</author><content>India&#8217;s top gymnast Dipa Karmakar has been forced out of the upcoming Commonwealth Games owing to the career-threatening knee injury she picked up last year, her coach Bisweshwar Nandi said on Tuesday.&#8220;She is not yet ready for a tournament like the Commonwealth Games. So, the target is to make her fully ready for the Asian Games (August 18-September 2),&#8221; Nandi told PTI.Karmakar, the first Indian female to compete in the Olympics where she finished a historic fourth in the women&#8217;s vault at the 2016 Rio Games, opted out of the CWG trials taking place at the Indira Gandhi Stadium in New Delhi.The Gold Coast Games take place from April 4-15.&#8221;She is fit but needs more time to be competition-ready. I would not call it a setback and she has taken it very sportingly,&#8221; added the coach.The 24-year-old had undergone an Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) surgery in April last year and is continuing to undergo a lengthy rehabilitation process. She has, however, started training, according to Nandi.The nature of the injury, which she picked up during a training camp, has not allowed her to compete since the Rio Olympics.She had scripted history at the 2014 Commonwealth Games in Glasgow, becoming the first Indian woman to win a medal in gymnastics in the mega-event.Karmakar had also secured a bronze in the 2015 Asian Championships.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T18:32:10+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Coaching is in my mind post-retirement: Yuvraj&#160;Singh</headline><description>Yuvraj Singh said that commentary is not his forte and coaching is something that interests him. The southpaw also said that he likes being a pillar of strength to people.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Veteran Indian batsman Yuvraj Singh has always remained optimistic of making a comeback in the Indian team despite form and fitness eluding him for past few seasons. While he did make a brief return in 2016, he failed to last long. However, in the latest interaction with the media, Yuvraj finally revealed his post-retirement plans and said that coaching is one area which is in his scheme of things. Stating that he would love to identify underprivileged kids and focus on their sport and education, Yuvraj maintained that cancer will be another area where he will look to work.Stating that commentary is not his forte, Yuvraj said, &#8220;Cancer (YouWeCan Foundation) is going to be my area of work in the future. I love supporting young kids, I like interacting with the younger generation. Coaching is in my mind. I would identify underprivileged kids and focus on their sport and education. Education is as important as sport. You need to focus on both. Sport should not come at the cost of education.&#8221;On his future with the Indian team, Yuvraj spoke to Sportstar live and said, &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to leave the game with any regret, thinking I should have played for some more years. I want to go when I feel it is the right time to go, when I feel I have done my best and I could not have done any more than this. I am still playing because I am enjoying playing cricket, not just because I have to play for India or I have to play the IPL. The motivation is definitely to play for India. I feel two or three IPLs are left in me.&#8221;&#8220;The journey has been nice. I have been a fighter, taking on tough situations. I like being a pillar of strength to people, for those suffering from cancer or going through other issues in life. I want to be known as someone who never gave up. Whether I play for India or not, I will give my 100 per cent on the field,&#8221; he concluded by saying.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:51:04+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>North Korea dials down border propaganda after PyeongChang Games&#160;open</headline><description>North and South Korea have been using large speakers to send a sonic barrage of music, news and propaganda at each other since early 2016.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>North Korea have lowered the volume of its border propaganda broadcasts at the inter-Korean Demilitarised Zone (DMZ) since Friday&#8217;s Winter Olympics opening ceremony, a senior military official stationed at the border told Reuters on Tuesday.North and South Korea have been using large speakers to send a sonic barrage of music, news and propaganda at each other since early 2016, when the South restarted its broadcasts in retaliation to North Korea&#8217;s fourth nuclear test that January.&#8220;I still hear it, but it is much less than before,&#8221; said the official who is stationed on the southern side of the border and spoke on condition of anonymity.It was not immediately clear if South Korea had also turned down the volume of its broadcasts.North Korean leader Kim Jong Un wants to boost the &#8220;warm climate of reconciliation and dialogue&#8221; with South Korea after his younger sister Kim Yo Jong led a three-day visit to the Games, North Korean state media said on Tuesday.The Games are being held at the ski resort of Pyeongchang, about 80 km (50 miles) south of the border.Mats Engman, a former major general who headed the Swedish delegation of the Neutral Nations Supervisory Committee in the DMZ until 2017, said any lowering or cessation of the broadcasts would be a small positive step toward dialogue.Engman, who now works for the Stockholm-based Institute for Security and Development Policy, said the broadcasts had limited military value and could be irritating.&#8220;When you live and work in the DMZ for longer periods and are exposed to an almost constant broadcast of propaganda, it may also negatively affect your judgment,&#8221; he added.&#8220;It can sometimes make it difficult for our officers to sleep, which in the long run makes people frustrated and irritated.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:29:34+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Blame players, not Mauricio Pellegrino, for Southampton&#8217;s slump: Oriol&#160;Romeu</headline><description>Southampton players, and not manager Mauricio Pellegrino, must take the blame for the Premier League club's dismal form, midfielder Oriol Romeu has said.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Southampton players, and not manager Mauricio Pellegrino, must take the blame for the Premier League club&#8217;s dismal form, midfielder Oriol Romeu has said.Pellegrino has come under increasing pressure as Southampton have won only one of their last 14 league games, and five overall, to drop into the relegation zone with 11 matches remaining in the campaign.&#8220;It&#8217;s not the manager&#8217;s problem,&#8221; Romeu told British media. &#8220;We are the ones playing, and the ones that have to change this.&#8221;With teams in the bottom-half being separated by close margins, Southampton lie four points behind 11th-placed Watford and Romeu has urged his team mates to solve their problems and climb up the table as the relegation battle heats up.&#8220;This season we have conceded too many easy goals. Then closing the game down, we have had too many times when we have lost points in the last minutes, so we need to know how to close the games, how to play under pressure, and then we will know how to get points,&#8221; Romeu added.&#8220;It is going to be very, very tight until the end (of the season). Every point is going to be important.&#8221;Southampton take on West Bromwich Albion in the fifth round of the FA Cup on Saturday before returning to league action against seventh-placed Burnley on Feb. 24.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:24:06+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Winter Olympics 2018: Brilliant Marcel Hirscher claims elusive first gold&#160;medal</headline><description>Marcel Hirscher, the greatest skier of his generation, ended his long wait for an Olympic gold medal when the Austrian claimed top spot in the men's combined event.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Marcel Hirscher, the greatest skier of his generation, ended his long wait for an Olympic gold medal when the Austrian claimed top spot in the men&#8217;s combined event after a blistering slalom run on Tuesday.Hirscher, who has won the last six overall World Cup titles and is poised to claim a seventh, climbed from an unexpectedly high 12th place after the downhill segment at the Jeongseon Alpine Centre to pip France&#8217;s Alexis Pinturault by 0.23 seconds.The Austrian&#8217;s previous best in the Olympics was a silver medal in slalom at Sochi four years ago.&#8220;I&#8217;m super happy because now this stupid question (about whether) I&#8217;m thinking that my career is perfect without a gold medal is gone away,&#8221; he told reporters.&#8220;I killed it. It is something special but really unexpected. We were not sure two weeks ago if I would compete in the combined or not.&#8221;The Austrian was forced to hold back his joy for a few moments after team mate Matthias Mayer, who was within touching distance, made a strong start to his slalom but forked a gate and fell.The 28-year-old Hirscher, who has said this would be his last Olympics, then sprinted out into the finishing area to celebrate his triumph.Victor Muffat-Jeandet completed a good day for French skiers by claiming the bronze medal behind compatriot Pinturault in an event that brings together a downhill stage and then a slalom section to test the all-round skills of competitors.Hirscher has won 10 World Cup races in slalom and giant slalom this season leaving Pinturault delighted to have just finished so close to the winner.&#8220;I&#8217;m really, really happy. Marcel has been unbeatable&#8230; so I really had to try hard and at least it was only two tenths. I can only be happy and proud,&#8221; he said.Muffat-Jeandet said he had paid the price for a lacklustre downhill effort, where he finished 20th, more than a second behind Hirscher.&#8220;I was really disappointed and angry with my downhill run. In skiing you have to do two full runs and with guys like Pinturault and Hirscher, if you do one bad run it&#8217;s not enough for the podium,&#8221; the Frenchman said.SVINDAL WITHDRAWS
Norway&#8217;s Aksel Svindal, who was second after the downhill segment behind Germany&#8217;s Thomas Dressen, surprisingly decided not to run the slalom leg.Team-mate Aleksanderr Aamodt Kilde said the 35-year-old Svindal had been wary about damaging his knee, which he has had long-running problems with and had operated on last year.&#8220;He has this knee, you know. So he tried on the warm-up but, you know, icy conditions, really, really bumpy, so he decided not to risk the other races by skiing slalom,&#8221; he said.Early leader Dressen, who has little slalom pedigree, finished in ninth position on a day when organisers were delighted to finally get action underway following 48 hours of weather postponements.With strong winds still a concern, the competition went ahead with an adjusted downhill stage, racing lower down the course at the designated super-G start and using the &#8216;blue wind line&#8217; which made for easier jumps.Dressen was first out and completed the course in one minute, 19.24 seconds and Hirscher, second down, was 1.32 seconds slower.The winds soon whipped up and caused problems on the relatively benign jumps, however.Russian Pavel Trikhichev and American Ryan Cochran-Siegle both crashed out after clipping gates.Italian Peter Fill somehow managed to land safely when the wind caught him midway through a jump and forced him into an awkward position, but he later crashed out in the slalom.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:10:30+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>West Brom striker Daniel Sturridge faces two weeks out, says manager Alan&#160;Pardew</headline><description>Sturridge, who joined West Brom on loan from Liverpool in January, picked up the knock during his third appearance for the bottom-placed side.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>West Bromwich Albion striker Daniel Sturridge is expected to make a quick return from the hamstring injury he sustained in the opening minutes of Monday&#8217;s 3-0 Premier League defeat by champions Chelsea, manager Alan Pardew has said.The England international, who joined West Brom on loan from Liverpool in January, picked up the knock during his third appearance for the bottom-placed side.&#8220;We need him up and running as it&#8217;s goals we&#8217;ve struggled with,&#8221; Pardew said after the match.&#8220;He felt his hamstring after a 60 metre sprint in the first moments of the game. We&#8217;ll have to nurse him. He won&#8217;t play next week but hopefully the week after.&#8221; The 28-year-old&#8217;s injury is a blow for West Brom, who have struggled to find the net throughout the campaign.West Brom play Southampton in the fifth round of the FA Cup on Saturday followed by a league fixture against Huddersfield Town on Feb. 24.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:08:56+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Rochdale&#8217;s Keith Hill dismisses pitch criticism ahead of Tottenham Hotspur&#160;clash</headline><description>Rochdale manager Keith Hill has dismissed criticism of the club's home pitch by Tottenham Hotspur counterpart Mauricio Pochettino.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Rochdale manager Keith Hill has dismissed criticism of the club&#8217;s home pitch by Tottenham Hotspur counterpart Mauricio Pochettino, saying the Argentine&#8217;s comments were a &#8220;low blow&#8221; and an &#8220;easy punch&#8221; ahead of Sunday&#8217;s FA Cup fifth-round match.The League One (third tier) club beat Millwall in the fourth round on a heavily-sanded pitch at the Crown Oil Arena this month to set up a meeting with Spurs.The Premier League team&#8217;s manager called for the Football Association to look into the matter last week after seeing pictures and said that the state of the pitch was a &#8220;massive risk&#8221; for players and inadequate for an FA Cup match.&#8220;I&#8217;m assured the pitch is going to be good,&#8221; Hill told the BBC. &#8220;It just seems to me it was an easy punch to hit us with. It was a bit of a low blow because a lot of work went into preparing the pitch and making sure it was playable. The pitch wasn&#8217;t a risk&#8230;. With respect to Pochettino, he&#8217;s got a right to comment on the pictures that were presented to him. But we are making sure that the playing surface is as perfect as it possibly can be.&#8221;Rochdale plan to lay down a new pitch before Tottenham&#8217;s visit and Hill is hoping his players can train on the new surface ahead of the Spurs game.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:02:08+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Winter Olympics 2018: Flag bearer Pita Taufatofua worried about cyclone that hit&#160;Tonga</headline><description>Taufatofua thanked people on Facebook for their messages of support and said he still hasn't heard if friends and family are safe.</description><author>AP</author><content>Olympic flag bearer Pita Taufatofua is concerned about his home country of Tonga after it was hit by a cyclone that destroyed Parliament House as well as churches and homes.The 34-year-old cross-country skier thanked people on Facebook for their messages of support and said he still hasn&#8217;t heard if friends and family are safe.Taufatofua gained international attention at the Winter Olympics when he marched bare chested into the opening ceremony carrying his country&#8217;s flag. He also marched bare chested in the opening ceremony of the 2016 Summer Games in Rio, albeit in more mild conditions.Now that he&#8217;s in South Korea preparing to compete, part of him wishes he was back home with his countrymen. In the meantime, he is looking to help raise funds for the damaged country.He competed in the Summer Olympics in taekwondo and decided to try his hand at cross-country skiing. He only picked up the sport within the last two years, but managed to qualify for the games on his last attempt.He&#8217;s not expected to compete for the medal.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:59:14+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Kept well on difficult wickets and showed character by opening the innings: Parthiv&#160;Patel</headline><description>Parthiv Patel believes that he showed a lot of character and kept well in the tough conditions in the third Test at Johannesburg.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>The South African tour proved to be quite a tough assignment for India&#8217;s wicketkeeper-batsman Parthiv Patel. However, the southpaw believes that he showed a lot of character and kept well in the tough conditions. Patel was roped into the Inda squad after&#160;Wriddhiman Saha was injured mid-way in the Test series.&#8220;I thought I kept well on that difficult wicket in the third Test at Johannesburg where the ball was keeping up and down. I also showed a lot of character by opening the innings (in the second essay) and tried to contribute as much as I could both as a batsman and keeper,&#8221; TOI quoted Parthiv as saying.Explaining the dropped chances, he said, &#8220;If you watch those attempts, they were not easy ones. It was a 50-50 chance and as long as you are putting in your full effort into it and staying committed &#8211; no one says anything. That was the feedback I got from the team.&#8221;Reflecting on the performance during the Test series, he said, &#8220;The result might not have gone in our favour but I thought we played really well. During every session, the talk in the middle and in the dressing-room was about winning. There was a lot of positive intent which kept the boys on top of their game.&#8221;Meanwhile, Parthiv Patel is all set to turn out for the Royal Challengers Bangalore in the IPL which begins in April and is excited to play alongside skipper Virat Kohli. &#8221; &#8220;Virat brings a huge amount of positivity into the team and to the dressing-room. He always leads by example and the team rallies around him,&#8221; Parthiv said.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:55:50+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>Ben Stokes pleads not guilty to affray charge for Bristol nightclub&#160;brawl</headline><description>Ben Stokes pleaded not guilty to affray charge for an incident back in September that left a man with a fractured eye socket.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Ben Stokes, who was charged with affray following an incident in the city of Bristol last September, pleaded not guilty on grounds of self-defense. The 26-year old England cricketer arrived at Bristol Magistrates&#8217; Court in a silver people-carrier with blacked out windows.The case will now be heard by the Bristol Crown Court on March 12. This means that Stokes, who has missed the Ashes after being suspended by the England Cricket Board due to the brawl incident, would be able to play in the ODI series against New Zealand.Ryan Ali and Ryan Hale, who were also involved in the incident, have pleaded not guilty as well. All the three accused have been released on unconditional bail by District Judge Simon Cooper. It is alleged that the fighting incident outside the nightclub had left a 27-year-old man with a fractured eye socket.Stokes had earlier said in a Facebook statement that he was keen to have the opportunity to clear his name from the case. &#8220;I am keen to have an opportunity to clear my name but, on advice, the appropriate time to do this is when the case comes to trial. The CPS&#8217; decision to charge me, as well as Ryan Ali and Ryan Hale, at least means that my account of what happened that night can come out in court and be made public. Until then, my focus is verymuch on cricket.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:49:10+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>Olympic Channel to livestream PyeongChang 2018 in Indian&#160;sub-continent</headline><description>The ongoing Winter Olympic Games in PyeongChang, South Korea will be streamed live in India and the sub-continent by online media platform, the Olympic Channel.</description><author>PTI</author><content>The ongoing Winter Olympic Games in PyeongChang, South Korea will be streamed live in India and the sub-continent by online media platform, the Olympic Channel.The announcement was made by the International Olympic Committee (IOC), the Olympic Channel said in a statement.The platform will present 1350 hours of coverage across India, which includes 870 hours of live streaming and video on-demand of all competitions as well as the opening and closing Ceremonies. The Games got underway on February 8 and will run till February 25.The XXIII Winter Olympic Games features more than 3,000 athletes representing more than 90 countries competing in 102 medal events across 15 sports disciplines including alpine skiing, cross-country skiing, figure skating, ice hockey, luge, snowboarding and speedskating.The live streaming of competition will be available on olympicchannel.com.India is represented at the Games by veteran luger Shiva Keshavan, who came in 34th in his swansong appearance, and cross country skier Jagdish Singh who is scheduled to compete on Friday.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:37:16+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>New Zealand beat England by 12 runs in T20&#160;tri-series</headline><description>Trent Boult grabbed two wickets on successive balls to help New Zealand to a 12-run win over England in their Twenty20 tri-series match at Wellington Regional Stadium on Tuesday.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Trent Boult grabbed two wickets on successive balls to help New Zealand to a 12-run win over England in their Twenty20 tri-series match at Wellington Regional Stadium on Tuesday.Left-arm seamer Boult bowled Chris Jordan and then Liam Plunkett on the final two deliveries of the 18th over to reduce the visitors to 168 for eight in their pursuit of 197 for victory.Adil Rashid kept out the hat-trick delivery on the first ball of the final over but there was too much for the legspinner and Chris Wood to do and they finished on 184 for nine.&#8220;It was a must-win for us in terms of the series,&#8221; New Zealand captain Kane Williamson said in reference to their seven-wicket loss to Australia in their opening match. &#8220;This is a very strong England side and we had to play some really good cricket.&#8221;Australia have already qualified for the final at Eden Park on Feb. 21 after winning all three of their matches so far.Williamson anchored New Zealand&#8217;s 196 for five with 72 while he also shared in an 82-run second-wicket partnership with Martin Guptill, who scored 65 from 40 balls.Mark Chapman, who has also played international cricket for Hong Kong, and debutant Tim Seifert then did what they had been brought into the side to do with quick-fire cameos in the middle order.Chapman scored 20, while wicketkeeper Seifert hit two sixes in his six-ball innings of 14 to take the hosts to the equal highest Twenty20 international score on the ground.&#8220;We were able to build partnerships throughout that gave us momentum and the two debutants were outstanding,&#8221; Williamson added. &#8220;They showed their power which allowed us to get an above-par total.&#8221;Alex Hales got England&#8217;s run chase off to a fast start with 47 from 24 balls before Dawid Malan gave England hope for victory as he scored 59 from 40 deliveries. Malan&#8217;s dismissal in the 17th over with the visitors needing 39 runs for victory, effectively ended their chances.&#8220;It was maybe 10 to 15 runs too many &#8230; and we didn&#8217;t bowl as well as we could have,&#8221; England captain Jos Buttler said.&#8220;We got a fantastic start with Alex and that partnership with Malan, we needed to just extend a bit longer then we didn&#8217;t get those cameos in the middle order.&#8221;New Zealand face in Australia the next game of the series in Auckland on Friday.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:44:15+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>Tokyo 2020 Games budget to benefit from fresh&#160;reforms</headline><description>The Tokyo 2020 Olympics will benefit from a fresh batch of IOC reforms, despite having already slashed their initial budget by roughly $2.5 billion, the IOC said on Tuesday.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>The Tokyo 2020 Olympics will benefit from a fresh batch of International Olympic Committee (IOC) reforms, despite having already slashed their initial budget by roughly $2.5 billion, the IOC said on Tuesday.The Games budget spiralled dangerously out of control a few years after Japan were awarded the event in 2013, forcing major revisions as potential future hosts, already concerned about the massive costs involved, were discouraged.A set of 118 reforms, named &#8216;the New Norm&#8217; and approved by the IOC session in Pyeongchang last week, are designed to drive down costs for future Summer Games hosts by around $1 billion.They would also provide some savings for Tokyo, the IOC&#8217;s Coordination Commission for Tokyo head John Coates said, even though all the reforms would only be in place at the 2024 Paris Games awarded to the French capital last September.&#8220;We have got some ideas (on the size of the savings) for Tokyo but we will continue to push,&#8221; Coates told reporters when asked how much money Tokyo was set to save from the partial implementation of the reforms.He did not name a figure or percentage for this amount.&#8220;I think the Tokyo revenues are secure but we want to make sure they (Games organisers) do not regard that as a comfort zone. We want to continue to drive and make savings,&#8221; he added.Tokyo&#8217;s overall budget, after several revisions, now stands at $12.6 billion, of which $5.6 billion are the organising committee&#8217;s budget for staging the Games.The IOC contributes some $1.7 billion in cash and services to the organising committee.The Japanese capital has already eclipsed all of its Olympic predecessors in terms of domestic sponsorship proceeds, raking in close to $3 billion, almost three times more than any previous host city.&#8220;(Savings) are at $2.5 billion already,&#8221; Coates said. &#8220;I think there is a hesitancy (from Tokyo) particularly given the extraordinary revenues that are coming in from national sponsors&#8230; because they do not want to take any chances.&#8220;Money for the organising committee is not an issue. But we will keep pushing.&#8221;The reforms cover reduced costs for bidding for the Olympics as well as organising the Games. Bidders must also present specific legacy plans before they are awarded the event to avoid littering cities with white elephants, as is often the case.The IOC was alarmed by the withdrawal of four cities campaigning for the 2022 Winter Olympics over size and cost concerns, prompting a &#8220;complete rethink&#8221;, Coates said.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:12:57+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>NBA: Coach Steve Kerr takes backseat in Golden State Warriors&#8217; 129-83 win over Phoenix&#160;Suns</headline><description>Kerr turned over most of the coaching duties to his players on Monday night and they responded in fine fashion.</description><author>AP</author><content>With the grind of a long NBA season wearing on his team, Golden State Warriors coach Steve Kerr believed it was time for his players to hear a new voice in the huddle: their own.Kerr turned over most of the coaching duties to his players on Monday night and they responded in fine fashion, playing with more focus than they had in recent weeks in a 129-83 victory over the Phoenix Suns.&#8220;It&#8217;s the players&#8217; team,&#8221; Kerr said. &#8220;It&#8217;s their team and they have to take ownership of it. As coaches, our job is to nudge them in the right direction, guide them. We don&#8217;t control them. They determine their own fate. I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ve focused well the last month. It just seemed like the right thing to do.&#8221;Kerr said he told the players of his plan after the previous game and they ran the show for most of the day. Andre Iguodala took over at morning shootaround, JaVale McGee ran the computer for the film session and Iguodala, Draymond Green and David West got most of the work designing plays and running the huddle during timeouts.Kerr and his assistants handled the substitutions before allowing the players to take over from there.&#8220;It had to do with me trying to reach my team and I have not reached them the last month,&#8221; Kerr said. &#8220;They&#8217;re tired of my voice. I&#8217;m tired of my voice. I wasn&#8217;t reaching them so we figured this was a good night to pull something out of the hat.&#8221;After the game, Kerr made a point of seeking out Phoenix interim coach Jay Triano to tell him the move wasn&#8217;t made out of any disrespect for the Suns, who became the first team to reach 40 losses this season.&#8220;You have to do what you have to do to build your own team up,&#8221; Triano said. &#8220;If he thinks that helps them, I tip my hat.&#8221;Stephen Curry scored 22 points for the Warriors. Omri Casspi added 19 in a rare start in place of the injured Green and Kevin Durant had 17 as Golden State won its 12th straight in the series, its longest active streak against any team.Elfrid Payton scored 29 points in his second game since being acquired at the trade deadline from Orlando, but Phoenix still lost its sixth straight and 11th in the past 12 games.&#8220;We have to keep fighting,&#8221; Payton said. &#8220;We can&#8217;t hang our heads. That&#8217;s the great thing about the NBA, there&#8217;s another game in two days. So learn from it, get better ready to have a better effort.&#8221;Payton scored 16 points in the first quarter before Curry got on the scoreboard, but he got little help. Payton made his first seven shots, but his teammates started 1 for 15 and the Warriors managed to take a 25-24 lead by the end of the first after being outscored by 32 points in the first quarter of the previous three games.Curry scored 10 points in the second quarter as Golden State built a 17-point lead at the half and coasted the rest of the way.&#8220;We have so many smart basketball minds on our team,&#8221; Casspi said. &#8220;The guys really used this opportunity to run things they like.&#8221;TIP-INSSuns: G Devin Booker (hip pointer) missed his fourth straight game, and G Tyler Ulis (back) sat for the second straight game. &#8230; Phoenix has lost 12 straight in Oakland, last winning here on Feb. 7, 2011.Warriors: G Patrick McCaw, who has been spending time in the G League between NBA games trying to get his confidence back, scored nine points in the second quarter after having just eight in the previous 10 games. He then left the game with a sprained right wrist.QUOTABLE&#8220;I was horrible actually. I thought about a play and forgot the second option and had two guys on the wrong place on the board and I actually got a delay of game coming out of halftime because I was scrambling,&#8221; Curry said about his role as a coach.FATHER-SONCurry&#8217;s 22 points gave him and his father, Dell, a combined 28,883 points in their careers, tying Rick and Brent Barry for the third-most ever by a father-son combination, according to the Elias Sports Bureau. Joe and Kobe Bryant have the most of any duo with 38,895 (33,643 from Kobe).For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:12:37+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Loris Karius credits consistent game time for Liverpool&#160;resurgence</headline><description>Liverpool goalkeeper Loris Karius believes his consistent presence in the starting line-up during recent Premier League games has spurred his resurgence.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Liverpool goalkeeper Loris Karius believes his consistent presence in the starting line-up during recent Premier League games has spurred his resurgence.Karius and Simon Mignolet have battled to be Liverpool&#8217;s first-choice goalkeeper under manager Juergen Klopp but inconsistent performances by both shotstoppers have led the German boss to rotate them constantly.Karius has started the club&#8217;s last five league games, helping Liverpool notch three wins and keeping two clean sheets in the process.&#8220;I am feeling good and getting consistent game time helps a lot,&#8221; the 24-year-old is quoted as saying by The Telegraph. &#8220;In the last few games I have had more stuff to do and I have been able to make some saves, which gives you more confidence.&#8220;&#8230; I have had a lot of experience but it definitely helps when you play regularly instead of coming in and out of the team.&#8221;Karius impressed in Sunday&#8217;s 2-0 league win over Southampton with the help of Virgil van Dijk, who put in a commanding display in central defence on his return to his former club.&#8220;Virgil has played quite a bit now and with him in front we are getting more used to each other,&#8221; Karius added. &#8220;That&#8217;s important for the team. He is a great player. Of course he has to adapt a bit because our style is so different. We defend high and he needs to get used to Dejan (Lovren) and Joel (Matip). Individually, Virgil is a top player. That&#8217;s why Liverpool paid the price they did for him.&#8221;Liverpool travel to Porto in the first leg of their Champions League round of 16 tie on Wednesday and Karius, who is likely to start the match, is keen for the Merseyside club to take control.&#8220;Having the second game at home can be a real advantage for us,&#8221; Karius said.&#8220;But for it to be an advantage we need to put ourselves in a good position in the tie.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T15:56:59+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Jhulan Goswami ruled out of T20 series against South&#160;Africa</headline><description>Jhulan Goswami has been forced to withdraw from the five-match women's T20 series against South Africa due to a heel injury.</description><author>PTI</author><content>A heel injury has forced veteran India pacer Jhulan Goswami to withdraw from the five-match women&#8217;s T20 series against South Africa, starting in Potchefstroom on Tuesday.&#8220;Goswami suffered a heel injury and underwent an MRI scan on Monday,&#8221; said the BCCI in a statement.&#8220;The BCCI Medical Team in consultation with a local doctor felt that she needs rest for a couple of weeks to avoid any further impact on the bone. Upon her return, Goswami will consult a foot expert and will undergo her rehab process at the NCA in Bengaluru,&#8221; it added.Gowami picked up five wickets in the preceding three-match ODI series which India won 2-1.She did not feature in the third and final ODI after India had already secured the series. During the second ODI, she became the first female cricketer to take 2oo ODI wickets.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T15:38:28+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>India vs South Africa LIVE Score 5th ODI: India post 274/7 against South&#160;Africa</headline><description>India vs South Africa Live Cricket Score 5th ODI: Catch Live Cricket Score India vs South Africa 5th ODI from Port Elizabeth. IND vs SA Live Score.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>India vs South Africa Live Score 5th ODI: India once again scored low at the final 10 overs. That was the theme in the final 10 overs in the losing fourth ODI and the same could be the final result today as India lost the plot. From three down after 42 overs, India finished 274/7 after 50 overs with just 55 runs in the last ten. Rohit Sharma remained the highlight performer for India but his inning also saw its bit of blunders with Virat Kohli and Ajinkya Rahane getting run out. India&#8217;s lower middle over faltered once again much to the disappointment of the Indian support staff. Ngidi tipped the game in South Africa&#8217;s favour with four wickets as none of the Indian batsmen could provide a final flourish. India are eyeing a first ODI series win in South Africa and currently lead the series 3-1. Catch Live Cricket Score India vs South Africa 5th ODI from Port Elizabeth here. (India vs South Africa Live Scorecard)India vs South Africa Live Score 5th ODI in Port ElizabethKagiso Rabada's final over is worth just five runs. Bhuvneshwar Kumar remains unbeaten on 19 and Kuldeep Yadav on 2.&#160;India: 274/7 (Rohit 115*, Kohli 36; Ngidi 4/51) against South Africa in fifth ODI at Port ElizabethMahendra Singh Dhoni's quest to push the tempo in the penultimate over doesn't work out. First ball goes for a four but he's dismissed off the second. Ngidi once again and well taken catch by Markram. Moving forward and on full stretch to take a smart catch. India are seven downAnother edge, another set batsman, another catch, another blow for India. Shreyas Iyer departs for 30 and Ngidi strikes once again. Short and wide, Iyer's foot not in position for the shot and it is edged behind to Klaasen. The Ngidi-Klaasen combination once again. India go from 236/3 to 238/6Golden duck for Hardik Pandya. Ngidi turns his poor day at the office into a fantastic one with Rohit and now Pandya. India's quest for a big score has been hurt significantly now. Double blow for India. 300 looks a tough ask nowRohit Sharma departs for 115. That was a fantastic delivery from Ngidi and Rohit has edged it behind to Klaasen. Worst time for India to lose Rohit here. Tried to slash it but it came into him and cramped for room, Rohit can only muster an edge behind. Extra bounce, came in and India lose their fourthHUNDRED FOR ROHIT SHARMA! 17th ODI century for Rohit. 101* from 107 balls - 10 fours, four sixes. That's his second ODI century against South Africa and first at this venue. Not been a convincing series for him but he could well change that script today if he were to go on to take India to a massive score. This inning has seen it all - classy shots, edges, run outs, dropped late on but he's persisted. Flicks it off the pads and runs a double to bring up relieved expressions in the Indian dressing roomA great innings under pressure!! Congratulations on your 17th ODI &#128175;, @ImRo45. Time for some fireworks &#128293; now &#128526; #TeamIndia #SAvIND pic.twitter.com/Nqyik8lj2NDROPPED! SHAMSI DROPS ROHIT AT 96! Was a regulation catch for Shamsi at third man but he's let it go. Rohit ramped that ball for the third man region, was into Shamsi's hands and should have been curtains for the India vice-captain. But it has scooped out and allowed Rohit to bat onRohit Sharma survives a loud appeal for bat/glove, thigh pad and caught behind to Klaasen. After some deliberation, South Africa review. Rohit gestured to Iyer that it had hit his thigh pad. And so it did. UltraEdge confirms it.&#160;RAHANE RUN OUT! Ajinkya Rahane is off the blocks quickly even as Rohit kept sending him back. Back-to-back run outs for India. Rahane goes for 8. INDIA 176/3RUN OUT! A yes and then no from Rohit Sharma and Kohli's return to non-striker's end is short. South Africa get the breakthrough. IND 153/2. A seventh run out between Kohli and Rohit. Kohli goes for 36 and that is his first under-50 score this series. At the other end, Rohit is approaching a hundredRohit Sharma brings up his 35th ODI fifty. 50 from 50 balls, five boundaries and two sixes. Finally Ro-Hit ends his barren spell with the bat and adds fifty to his tally. First of the series for him and third against South AfricaThe game has slowed a bit in PE. Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma are rotating the strike but no boundaries are coming. India are 84 for 1 after 14 overs and scoring a rate of 6 runs per over.Virat Kohli takes a couple of small steps forward and makes a decent delivery from new bowler Adile Phehlukwayo as a overpitched one. A good cover drive for four from the Indian captainWe all know Rohit Sharma loves playing the pull shot. Ngidi bowls a short ball which is just at a perfect height for Rohit to pull. He does it and that lands way back into the stands . What a shot!South Africa have bowled 10 overs in this innings and India have reached 61 for 1. Scoring at just over run a ball. Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma at the crease. Change in bowling as Lungo Ngidi replaces Morkel50 up for India in that over but a wicket for South Africa too. India are 52 for 1 after 8 overs. Virat Kohli has joined Rohit Sharma in the middle. Morkel and Rabada continueGONE! Big wicket for South Africa. Dhawan has fallen in the trap. The previous ball was short and wide which Dhawan guided over gully for four. The next one is short and cramping Dhawan for room. He is late on the pull and the ball flies straight to deep fine-leg. India lose their first wicketIt was a slow and cautious start from the Indian openers but Rohit and Dhawan have now accumulated some quick runs and given India steady start. A flurry of boundaries from the openers.Rohit Sharma charges down the pitch and clobbers one over long-on for a massive six off Kagiso Rabada. That will give him a lot of confidence against Rabada. Stunning shot. India upping the ante hereFirst runs off Morkel's bowling! The last ball of his third over has been cut by Rohit Sharam through the point region and that has travelled quickly to the fence. Great shot from Rohit. India 17/0Rabada tried cramping Dhawan for room with short ball directed into his rib cage but the Indian opener pulls it for four. He then gets a deft touch on a pacy delivery which goes over slip cordon for another four. India 13/0Two maiden overs in a row from Morne Morkel. First one was to Shikhar Dhawan and this one is to Rohit Sharma. India are still five for no loss. Rohit played that over with more confidence and even middle a few shotsA magnficent cover drive from Shikhar Dhawan to end the second over from Kagiso Rabada. Leaning into the shot and with a brilliant follow-through. India five for no loss after two oversKagiso Rabada has got Rohit Sharma out three times in this ODI series and he is looking uneasy once again. But a flick to fine-leg and Rohit gets off the mark and off strikeMorne Morkel with a precise line and length to start the game. A maiden over from the South Africa bowler as Shikhar Dhawan tries to get his eye in. Rabada to share the new ballIndia openers Shikhar Dhawand and Rohit Sharma are out in the middle for the match. Morne Morkel will bowl the first over for South Africa. All setWhile the pitch is expected to wearout as the game goes one, the rain forecast in Port Elizabeth is the big reason for Markram to elect&#160; to bowl. With showers expected in the evening, the DLS will come into play and the team batting second is expected to benfit from thatAiden Markram, Hashim Amla, JP Duminy, AB de Villiers, David Miller, Heinrich Klaasen, Andile Phehlukwayo, Kagiso Rabada, Tabraiz Shamsi, Morne Morkel, Imran TahirRohit Sharma, Shikhar Dhawan, Virat Kohli, Ajinkya Rahane, Shreyas Iyer, MS Dhoni, Hardik Pandya, Bhuvneshwar Kumar, Kuldeep Yadav, Jasprit Bumrah, Yuzvendra ChahalVirat Kohli says that India are playing with an unchanged side while South Africa have been forced to make a change. Chris Morris has a stiff back and is replaced by Tabraiz ShamsiSouth Africa captain Aiden Markram has won the toss in Port Elizabeth and he has elected to bowl against India in the 5th ODI. Virat Kohli wanted to bowl first as well but toss not in his controlIndia are leading the six-match series 3-1. They have to win one more match and then they will claim the series. South Africa will be under pressure of the margin and this is a must win game for themWelcome to the coverage of the 5th ODI between India and South Africa from Port Elizabeth. India lead the series 3-1 and will like to win today and claim their first-ever series win in South Africa. But it won't be easy as the Proteas are fired up after their win the 4th ODI.</content><date>2018-02-13T20:19:28+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>Twenty20 could have a monopoly on cricket: Jos&#160;Buttler</headline><description>Jos Buttler feels cricket could become a one-format game in the future and hoped that administrators can find a way of making the Test game more popular.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>While the soaring popularity of T20 cricket might give fans across the globe a lot of joy but according to England wicketkeeper-batsman Jos Buttler, it could signal the end for other formats.Speaking to&#160;Sky Sports, Buttler said, &#8220;I feel cricket could become a one-format game in the future &#8211; whether that&#8217;s soon or in 15 to 20 years.&#8221;&#8220;Test cricket is still, for me, the pinnacle of cricket but T20 fills out stadiums and is easy to keep up with and follow. Everyone wants things faster these days and things evolve so maybe Twenty20 could have a monopoly on cricket,&#8221; he added.Reiterating the importance of Test cricket, he explained, &#8220;We all love the history of Test cricket &#8211; you will never have situations thrown up in T20 that Test cricket can do to you and you will never be tested as a player as you would in Test cricket. It&#8217;s a complete test of everything and it would be sad [if it disappeared], but as a product T20 is going from strength to strength.&#8221;&#8220;Hopefully, the administrators can find a way of making the Test game more popular &#8211; it&#8217;s awesome and I&#8217;d love to be playing in it,&#8221; Buttler went on add.Meanwhile, speaking on his personal form the right-hander&#160;revealed that being overlooked for the Ashes was a wake-up call for him. &#8220;Not making the Ashes squad was a wake-up call that I have slipped down the ladder in red-ball cricket and white-ball cricket is obviously my strength. I thought if I&#8217;m serious about playing red-ball cricket I could give up the white-ball stuff for two years and spend winters playing red ball, but I feel like there are too many opportunities to go down that route,&#8221; he concluded by saying.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:41:53+00:00</date><category>cricket</category></article><article><headline>Winter Olympics 2018: Snow Queen Chloe Kim dominates to take gold in women&#8217;s&#160;halfpipe</headline><description>Chloe Kim won her first Games gold as the teenage sensation romped to victory in the halfpipe at the Pyeongchang Winter Olympics on Tuesday.</description><author>AP</author><content>Gold medal already in hand and Olympic dream fully realized, Chloe Kim could have turned her third and final run in the women&#8217;s snowboarding final into a victory lap.Only she didn&#8217;t. She couldn&#8217;t. Gold medals are nice and all, but to the 17-year-old star, the journey is the point, not the destination. It&#8217;s about proving something. Not to quiet whatever doubters may remain in a sport where she&#8217;s stamping herself as an all-time great as a teenager, but to herself.So she went for it. She had no choice.&#8220;I knew that if I went home with a gold medal knowing I could do better, I wasn&#8217;t going to be satisfied,&#8221; Kim said.That shouldn&#8217;t be a problem. Kim turned her coronation into an exclamation point, stomping a pair of 1080 spins (three complete turns), then practically diving into a hug with American teammate and bronze medal winner Arielle Gold to seal a moment four years in the making.&#8220;I don&#8217;t really know what&#8217;s happening and I&#8217;m actually feeling a little anxious right now,&#8221; Kim said.&#160;&#8220;I&#8217;m a little overwhelmed. But this is the best outcome I could ever ask for and it&#8217;s been such a long journey. Ahhh, just going home with the gold is amazing.&#8221;So is her riding.Competing in front of her extended family, a group that included her Korean-born parents and her South Korean grandmother, and apparently on an empty stomach _ she actually tweeted during the competition that she was &#8220;hangry&#8221; after failing to finish her breakfast sandwich _ Kim put on a show that delivered on her considerable pre-Olympic hype. She put together a 93.75 during her first run, one that included just one 1080, not the two that have become her trademark. No matter. The perfection-flirting third run provided a cathartic exclamation point.&#8220;I knew that I did put down a really good first run, but I was also like, &#8216;I can do better than that. I can one up myself,'&#8221; Kim said.She&#8217;s the only one.Liu Jiayu took silver with an 89.75 to become the first Chinese snowboarder to medal at the Olympics. Gold, who pondered retirement last summer, overcame a dislocated shoulder suffered during training to edge teammate and three-time Olympic medalist Kelly Clark for third.Kim&#8217;s parents were born in South Korea and moved to the United States, putting their daughter in an interesting position heading into her first Olympics.While she understands the urge to build a narrative around her that turns her into a connective tissue of sorts between the host country and the one she calls home, it&#8217;s one she has politely sidestepped. She views herself as just a kid from Torrance, California, who likes music, the mall, ice cream and, oh, by the way, putting down the kind of gravity-escaping, physics challenging runs that have made her a dominant force in her sport.Kim would have made the Olympic team with ease four years ago, only to have the calendar get in the way. She was 13 at the time, too young to make the trip to Russia. She entered the quadrennium between the games with the kind of expectations reserved for the Shaun Whites of the snowboarding world. She has exceeded every one.Standing atop the hill at calm and brilliant Phoenix Snow Park _ a stark contrast to the windy mess that turned the women&#8217;s slopestyle final into an ugly, borderline unsafe and crash-filled mess 24 hours earlier _ Kim looked down at the crowd that included her parents, three sisters, three aunts, two cousins and her grandmother Moon Jung ae and proceeded to waste little time while turning the final into a global coming-out party.She drilled her opening set, throwing in a 1080 _ basically, three twists high above the pipe _ before following it with a pair of flips (or &#8220;corks&#8221;). Kim celebrated at the end, pumping her fists as &#8220;USA! USA!&#8221; chants rained down. When her score flashed, she clasped her hands atop her head and drank in the moment.Kim&#8217;s teammates made serious bids to give the Americans only their fourth-ever Olympic podium sweep.Gold, who dislocated her right shoulder during training for the Sochi Olympics and didn&#8217;t compete then barely made the 12-woman final, brushed off a fall during her first run and stomped an 85.75 on her third run. Clark, the 2002 Olympic champion still going strong at age 34, couldn&#8217;t quite catch Gold with an 83.50.Liu came the closest to providing Kim with a serious threat. She threw down a 89.75 during her first set to take the lead, only to watch Kim top it during her first run moments later.Liu then washed out on her last trip down the longest Olympic halfpipe since the sport made its debut in 1998, turning Kim&#8217;s last run into a victory lap. Rather than playing it safe, she went for it.Her No. 1 bib soaring into the South Korean sky, she put on a display that left the rest of the field and the thousands packed near the finish roaring their approval and vaulting her to a level of stardom she&#8217;s not quite sure she&#8217;s prepared for. Kim is well aware she&#8217;ll become a role model for other Korean American kids whether she wants the role or not.She&#8217;ll figure it out as she goes.&#8220;The one thing I learned was just give everything a shot,&#8221; she said. &#8220;You don&#8217;t want to live in regret. I feel like no regrets is the best way to go.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T15:23:28+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Renault enters esports with an eye on virtual&#160;F1</headline><description>Renault said it had joined forces with France's Team Vitality to compete in a programme of motorsport-based competitions.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Renault announced its entry into the world of esports on Monday and said it was also targeting the virtual Formula One championship.The French car manufacturer, which has its own F1 team that last won titles in 2006, said it had joined forces with France&#8217;s Team Vitality to compete in a programme of motorsport-based competitions.Renault Sport Team Vitality will participate in this year&#8217;s Rocket League Championship Series Europe, which has more than 25 million players.&#8220;We are also in discussion with F1 to compete in the Formula One eSports Series,&#8221; Renault said in a statement.
It added that Renault Sport Racing would give the esports team&#8217;s players access to its Formula One factory at Enstone, in central England, to train with racing drivers and technical staff.Formula One held its first eSports series finals in Abu Dhabi at the end of the 2017 season, with the title won by 18-year-old British kitchen manager Brendon Leigh after more than 63,000 contestants had entered worldwide.Renault is the first Formula One team to have an official esports tie-up, although McLaren&#8217;s twice world champion Fernando Alonso set up his own outfit last November.McLaren also recently recruited an official simulator driver through its World&#8217;s Fastest Gamer competition.Darren Cox, the man behind that, told Reuters last December he could see the current Grand Prix teams racing each other in the virtual world as well as the real one this year.&#8220;If you look at what the NBA (basketball) has done&#8230;they engaged the teams right at the beginning. So 17 of the NBA teams have got franchises for the virtual side of the sport and there&#8217;s a draft like in the real world.
&#8220;So expect something like that to come out of (Formula One owners) Liberty,&#8221; added Cox. &#8220;It&#8217;s happening now. Those conversations are being had.&#8221;Renault F1 Managing Director Cyril Abiteboul said the ties between motorsport and gaming were obvious, with both demanding mental strength and physical fitness in a competitive environment.&#8220;Last year&#8217;s exciting launch by FOM (Formula One Mnagement) of the Formula One eSports Series has accelerated the convergence of these two worlds and created opportunities for collaboration,&#8221; added the Frenchman.&#8220;Our drivers, and especially those who form part of the Renault Sport Academy programme, and Vitality&#8217;s own champions will be able to trade best practices.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T14:49:38+00:00</date><category>motor-sport</category></article><article><headline>UEFA Champions League: Managerial jobs at stake in Cristiano Ronaldo-Neymar&#160;showdown</headline><description>It's not just a place in the quarterfinals at stake for PSG and Madrid. The losing coach is likely to find himself out of work by the end of the season.</description><author>AP</author><content>The Champions League resumes with a mouthwatering meeting of the aristocrats and the disruptors of European soccer.The hosts: Real Madrid, the indisputable kings of the continent with 12 titles led by five-time world player of the year Cristiano Ronaldo.The visitors: Paris Saint-Germain, the upstarts who bulldozed soccer&#8217;s transfer record to hitch Neymar to the Qatari-funded mission to join soccer&#8217;s elite.The Santiago Bernabeu is the stage on Wednesday for Neymar&#8217;s return to Spain six months after the heir to Ronaldo&#8217;s throne was prized away from Barcelona for 222 million euros.&#8220;(Neymar and Ronaldo) are both quick, very strong one-on-one, they play quickly and put a lot of intensity into their games,&#8221; said PSG winger Angel Di Maria, a Champions League winner alongside Ronaldo at Madrid in 2014. &#8220;Ney is smaller, and that&#8217;s perhaps his advantage. But they are both capable of turning games.&#8221;Only one of the superstars can advance from the round of 16 games in Madrid and Paris over the next month.The 26-year-old Neymar is chasing the supreme status already attained by Ronaldo.&#8220;He lives and breathes goals,&#8221; Madrid coach Zinedine Zidane said of Ronaldo, underscoring the 33-year-old Portuguese forward&#8217;s enduring influence on the team. Ronaldo has helped Madrid win three of the last four Champions League titles, with two goals in last season&#8217;s final victory over Juventus.Juventus helps to open the knockout phase this week against Tottenham on Tuesday when Manchester City travels to Basel. Liverpool is away against Porto on Wednesday but it will take something special to seize the spotlight from the Spanish capital.&#8220;This tie,&#8221; Ronaldo said, &#8220;could define the whole season.&#8221;It&#8217;s not just a place in the quarterfinals at stake for PSG and Madrid. The losing coach is likely to find himself out of work by the end of the season.Only two months ago, Zidane lifted the Club World Cup for a second successive year but his job prospects could be dependent on winning a third successive Champions League title.So much has gone wrong domestically. Madrid languishes in fourth place and 17 points behind Barcelona in La Liga and is out of the Copa del Rey.In Paris, Unai Emery is still haunted by last season&#8217;s failures. He clung to power despite being deposed as French champions and an astonishing collapse at this stage to Barcelona.
&#8220;We&#8217;re stronger than last season,&#8221; Di Maria said.Certainly in France where PSG has pulled 12 points clear of defending champion Monaco.But while PSG can bully most teams, it is vulnerable against those playing with aggression and closing down high up the pitch. That was evident in a loss to Lyon last month when PSG panicked in defense and conceded a stoppage-time goal.PSG will be hoping the decision to invest so much of its resources in securing Neymar and Kylian Mbappe does not backfire against Madrid.Di Maria has been in stronger form than Mbappe recently, scoring four times in the last month compared to the 19-year-old forward&#8217;s solitary effort.Might it have been wiser to spend on protecting the shaky defense? For the trip to Spain, 32-year-old Lassana Diarra could be deployed as the holding midfielder even though Emery accepts he can&#8217;t last a full game.But Madrid has concerns in defense after conceding eight goals in its last five games, and Dani Carvajal is suspended after a yellow-card ploy backfired. While Carvajal had experience taking on Neymar in games against Barcelona, Zidane could be left relying on 19-year-old Achraf Hakimi.Madrid is protecting a formidable home record in Europe, having gone 17 matches unbeaten. But as Karim Benzema has been discovering, playing at home has its pitfalls.&#8220;I don&#8217;t know why there&#8217;s a section of our supporters that jeer Benzema,&#8221; Zidane said. &#8220;His fortunes will change.&#8221;Here is a closer look at the week&#8217;s other games.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T14:16:05+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>IPL 2018: Shane Warne to mentor Rajasthan&#160;Royals</headline><description>Shane Warne, who led Rajasthan Royals to a fairytale title finish in the first edition, announced that he would be mentoring the side in the coming edition.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Shane Warne announced his appointment as the team mentor for Indian Premier League team Rajasthan Royals for the 11th edition of the tournament. The former Australian legspinner, who led his side to a fairytale title finish in the first edition of the Indian Premier League in 2008, said, &#8220;Very excited to be joining the @rajasthanroyals in this years #IPL as team mentor!&#8221;The 48-year old also posted a video along with the announcement where he spoke about his memories with the IPL team. &#8220;Hello guys. Got a huge announcement that I promised. And that is that I will be joining Rajasthan Royals of the IPL in the season 2018 as a team mentor. I am very thankful for the opportunity that I have been given by the Royals. I am really looking forward to it. I have been involved with the Royals. I have so many memories, especially from 2008, when we won the inaugural year. The fans in India have always supported me throughout my career but they really got behind us in 2008 with the Rajasthan Royals,&#8221; said Warne, who has claimed 56 wickets in 52 IPL games.The former Australian player added, &#8220;As I said, great memories! The guys have done a wonderful job putting the squad together which has talented Indian players, International players, young players. It really is a wonderful squad and I think it can achieve some special things in 2018.&#8221;This one&#8217;s for you Warnie!!!
The First Royal &#128081; @ShaneWarne returns home. Let&#8217;s get the season started&#8230; &#128170;&#128293; #HallaBol #AbBajegaDanka #TheReturnOfTheFirstRoyal #IPL2018 pic.twitter.com/RuVN4cwb5O&#8212; Rajasthan Royals (@rajasthanroyals) February 13, 2018&#8220;So once again I am delighted to announce that I am team mentor for Rajasthan Royals. Thank you again for the opportunity and thank you for the support. I can&#8217;t wait to get there and remember the words &#8216;Halla Bol&#8217;!&#8221; he concluded.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T13:29:30+00:00</date><category>ipl-2018</category></article><article><headline>Donald Trump has a tweet for everything, but none yet for Winter&#160;Olympics</headline><description>Trump's silence on the PyeongChang Games mirrors his relative lack of comment during the 2016 Summer Olympics in Rio de Janeiro.</description><author>AP</author><content>President Donald Trump has a tweet for just about everything, but he&#8217;s got nothing so far for Team USA a few days into the 2018 Olympic Games.Trump sent a pair of tweets last week about the games that opened Friday in Pyeongchang (PYUHNG&#8217;-chahng), South Korea. Both complimented the host country.Vice President Mike Pence returned to Washington late Saturday after leading a U.S. delegation to Friday&#8217;s opening ceremony.Trump&#8217;s daughter, Ivanka Trump, who serves as an unpaid adviser to her father, is on tap to lead a delegation to the Feb. 25 closing ceremony.Trump&#8217;s silence on the Pyeongchang Games mirrors his relative lack of comment during the 2016 Summer Olympics in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. He sent one tweet wishing the athletes good luck.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T12:50:11+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article><article><headline>Donald Young accuses Ryan Harrison of racial slur during New York Open&#160;match</headline><description>Young accused Harrison of commenting on him being a black tennis player in the middle of the match.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>After Donald Young failed to get past sixth-seed Ryan Harrison in the first round of New York Open, the 28-year old took to Twitter and accused his opponent Harrison of commenting on Young being a black tennis player in the middle of the match.Young, who did not reveal the exact words spoken by Harrison, wrote in the tweet, &#8220;I&#8217;m shocked and disappointed, Ryan Harrison, to hear you tell me how you really feel about me as a black tennis player in the middle of our NY match. I thought this was supposed to be an inclusive gentleman&#8217;s sport.&#8221;I&#8217;m shocked and disappointed, Ryan Harrison, to hear you tell me how you really feel about me as a black tennis player in the middle of our NY match. I thought this was supposed to be an inclusive gentleman&#8217;s sport.&#8212; Donald Young Jr (@Yimlife1313) 13 February 2018Harrison, the last champion of the Memphis Open, beat Young 6-3, 7-6 (4) on Monday in his first-round match at the ATP 250 event. The final edition of the Memphis Open was won by Harrison, who served 10 aces in his victory over Young.Last month at the Australian Open, Young went down 6-1, 6-2, 6-4 to Serbian tennis star Novak Djokovic in the first round.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T12:30:38+00:00</date><category>tennis</category></article><article><headline>Manchester City no longer Champions League laggards, says Vincent&#160;Kompany</headline><description>City won the English Premier League title in 2012 and 2014 and are almost certain to win it again this season, but their forays into Europe's top club competition have been relatively disappointing.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Big-spending Manchester City finally feel at home in the Champions League after six years of frustration and are ready to make their mark, defender Vincent Kompany said on Monday.City won the English Premier League title in 2012 and 2014 and are almost certain to win it again this season, but their forays into Europe&#8217;s top club competition have been relatively disappointing.They are in the Champions League for the seventh successive season but their previous efforts have included two group stage eliminations, three last 16 exits and a semi-final, in 2015-16.&#8220;There was a lack of experience, we have been caught out a few times when we shouldn&#8217;t have been, but things have changed now,&#8221; Kompany told reporters as his side prepared to face FC Basel in Tuesday&#8217;s round of 16 first leg.&#8220;If ever the club is ready to feel at home in the competition, then it&#8217;s now. If every year we can go with the same confidence, eventually we will get there.&#8220;In previous years, we&#8217;ve felt how difficult it was. We are trying to break into a well-established order, Bayern Munich, Barcelona and Real Madrid&#8230;&#8221; he added.Barca and Real Madrid have each won the Champions League three times in the past 10 years while Bayern have lifted the trophy once in that time and lost in two other finals.The Belgian is in his 10th season at the club and said he had never experienced such high levels of intensity in a team. City are 16 points clear at the top of the Premier League and through to the League Cup final and FA Cup fifth round.&#8220;The key thing I&#8217;ve noticed is the ability to switch back on for every single game, the motivation and respect for the opponent&#8230; that&#8217;s one thing I haven&#8217;t experienced in any of the teams I&#8217;ve been in before,&#8221; he said.&#8220;From game to game, I have never experienced these levels of focus and intensity through the team.&#8221;City coach Pep Guardiola said forward Leroy Sane has returned to training after suffering an ankle injury in their FA Cup tie at Cardiff City, having previously been expected to be sidelined for seven weeks.&#8220;He&#8217;s worked a lot, he&#8217;s not in perfect condition, but he has gained a lot of time and he wants to help us,&#8221; Guardiola said. Asked for further details on how Sane had recovered so quickly, the Spaniard replied: &#8220;He&#8217;s young.&#8221;For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T11:38:49+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>WWE Raw results: Kurt Angle announces first-ever 7-man Elimination Chamber match after Finn Balor, Seth Rollins&#160;qualify</headline><description>Both Finn B&#225;lor and Seth Rollins simultaneously pinned Bray Wyatt in Raw&#8217;s main event.</description><author>Express Web Desk</author><content>Raw General Manager Kurt Angle came up with the solution of holding the first-ever 7-man Elimination Chamber after&#160;both Finn B&#225;lor and Seth Rollins simultaneously pinned Bray Wyatt in Raw&#8217;s main event.While four men were already booked for the Fatal 5-Way that pitted Superstars who lost their initial Men&#8217;s Elimination Chamber qualifiers, Rollins pleaded his way in to finally be added by Angle. All five men &#8211; Balor, Apollo Crews, Matt Hardy, Wyatt and Rollins &#8211; had a good chance from what it looked like at the beginning, with Rollins and Wyatt pinned as favourites.Balor barged in on a fight between Rollins and Wyatt which turned into a showdown between Rollins-Hardy and Wyatt-Balor. Eventually, Balor and Rollins teamed up to launch an attack on Crews and Wyatt. In the midst of the confusing act, Wyatt suffered a simultaneous pinfall from both The Kingslayer and The Extraordinary Man.The contest ended in an indecisive fashion as Raw went off air without a winner being declared. In a post-Raw confrontation on Facebook Live, Angle declared that both Rollins and B&#225;lor would be allowed into the Chamber, turning the bout into a 7-man contest for the first time ever.Other results:
John Cena def. Intercontinental Champion The Miz (loser enters the Men&#8217;s Elimination Chamber Match first)
The Revival def. Luke Gallows &amp; Karl Anderson
Bayley def. Sasha Banks
Mandy Rose &amp; Sonya Deville def. Raw Women&#8217;s Champion Alexa Bliss &amp; Mickie James
Roman Reigns def. Raw Tag Team Champion SheamusFor all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T11:03:23+00:00</date><category>wwe-wrestling</category></article><article><headline>USA to play France, Ireland and Paraguay in football&#160;friendlies</headline><description>US will face World Cup-bound France in one of three friendlies before World Cup in Russia as they seek to fill in an empty schedule after they failed to qualify.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>The US men&#8217;s team will face World Cup-bound France in one of three friendlies before the finals in Russia as they seek to fill in an empty schedule after they failed to qualify for the global showpiece for the first time since 1986.The US will also host Paraguay on March 27 in North Carolina before heading to Europe for games against Ireland in Dublin on June 2 and 1998 World Cup winners France in Lyon on June 9.US Soccer, still smarting from their failure to qualify for the finals, said they had planned their most demanding non-tournament schedule ever for the team and expected to announce more &#8220;high-profile&#8221; friendlies in September, October and November.&#8220;Serious about the ambition to field a men&#8217;s team considered among the best in the world, US Soccer will continue to seek matches against world-class soccer nations and in world-class venues,&#8221; US Soccer said in a statement.Coach Bruce Arena resigned last October after they failed to qualify for the finals and new US Soccer president Carlos Cordeiro, who was elected at the weekend, said a still-to-be-hired general manager would lead the search for a new coach. The World Cup finals run from June 14-July 15.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T10:43:58+00:00</date><category>football</category></article><article><headline>Winter Olympics 2018: Many skaters depart PyeongChang Games between team, individual&#160;events</headline><description>The way the figure skating program is set up, there is a long break between the team competition and the ice dance and women's competitions.</description><author>AP</author><content>If you&#8217;re leaving PyeongChang on Tuesday morning, check out the folks sitting next to you. They might be wearing Olympic medals.The way the figure skating program is set up, there is a long break between the team competition and the ice dance and women&#8217;s competitions. The pairs program begins Wednesday and the men take the ice for their individual event Friday, but the rest are off until next week.So, most of the ice dancers and women from powerhouse countries such as Canada were leaving the craziness of the Olympic sphere Tuesday for calmer surroundings. In their case, dancers Tessa Virtue and Scott Moir and the women&#8217;s contingent of Kaetlyn Osmond, Gabrielle Daleman and Larkyn Austman were on their way back to Seoul for a few days of work in an out-of-the-way rink.Virtue and Moir, along with Osmond and Daleman, were instrumental in the Canadians winning gold in the team event. The Olympic Athletes from Russia took silver and the US won bronze.&#8220;We&#8217;ll be going to our training site outside of the Olympic structure, so to speak, and we&#8217;ll be able to take our experience of competing in this team event to our advantage,&#8221; said Moir, who along with Virtue are aiming for a fifth Olympic medal. &#8220;It&#8217;s a huge advantage that we&#8217;ve been out there.&#8221;Mirai Nagasu became only the third woman and first American to land a triple axel in Olympic competition , helping the US secure its bronze. Now, she&#8217;s headed to a secret location outside the host city of Gangneung with teammates Karen Chen and Bradie Tennell to keep the jump sharp.They&#8217;ll be joined there by three ice dance teams that are podium contenders: siblings Maia and Alex Shibutani, who also skated in the team event; Madison Chock and Evan Bates; and national champs Madison Hubbell and Zach Donohue, who have been skating the best of their careers.On the flip side, some of the men competing this week have just arrived.Japanese sensation Yuzuru Hanyu, who is bidding to become the first back-to-back gold medalist since Dick Button in 1952, was greeted by a mob at Incheon International Airport on Monday night. One of his biggest rivals, Javier Fernandez of Spain, took the ice for the first time Tuesday morning.Why not spend the entire time soaking up the Olympic experience? Besides the pressure, there is a more practical consideration: ice time. The venue for figure skating doubles as the facility for short-track speedskating, so there are limited opportunities for teams to practice.Sometimes, that entails waking up at 5 a.m. to be ready for 6:30 a.m. practices. Or heading back to the rink after dinner for a late-night session at odds with the morning competitions.&#8220;We&#8217;ll be able to get a lot more practice time,&#8221; Alex Shibutani explained of the Americans&#8217; choice to train elsewhere over the next few days. &#8220;We&#8217;ll be able to relax a little bit before coming back here next week and getting ready for our individual event.&#8221;The Russian athletes, including medal favorites Evgenia Medvedeva and Alina Zagitova, are flying to the coastal Japanese city of Niigata to fine-tune their programs. Likewise, the Japanese women and ice dancers are heading home for a few days before returning to the Korean peninsula to compete.&#8220;Nothing is proven yet,&#8221; Zagitova said. &#8220;I still need to skate well in the individual event. I need to psychologically stay calm so that I can go out like any other competition.&#8221;Turns out leaving the Olympic atmosphere is a popular way to do it.For all the latest Sports News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T10:34:51+00:00</date><category>sport-others</category></article></sports>











<technology><article><headline>Cigar-shaped interstellar asteroid &#8216;Oumuamua&#8217; experienced violent past:&#160;Study</headline><description>A study suggests that the cigar-shaped asteroid, Oumuamua, has been travelling through the Universe for billions of years.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Oumuamua &#8211; the first known interstellar object to visit our solar system &#8211; has experienced a violent past, causing it to tumble around chaotically for many billions of years, a study suggests. The object flew through our solar system in October and was originally thought to be a comet, then it was later revealed as a cigar-shaped asteroid.Since October, researchers at the Queen&#8217;s University Belfast have been analysing the brightness measurements of the object. They discovered that Oumuamua was not spinning periodically like most of the small asteroids and bodies that we see in our solar system. Instead, it is tumbling, or spinning chaotically, and could have been for many billions of years.While it is difficult to pinpoint the exact reason for this, it is thought that Oumuamua impacted with another asteroid before it was fiercely thrown out of its system and into interstellar space. &#8220;Our modelling of this body suggests the tumbling will last for many billions of years to hundreds of billions of years before internal stresses cause it to rotate normally again,&#8221; said Wes Fraser, Queen&#8217;s University Belfast in the UK.&#8220;While we don&#8217;t know the cause of the tumbling, we predict that it was most likely sent tumbling by an impact with another planetesimal in its system, before it was ejected into interstellar space,&#8221; said Fraser. Until now, scientists had been puzzled that Oumuamua&#8217;s colour varied between measurements. However, the research has now revealed that its surface is spotty and that when the long face of the cucumber-shaped object was facing telescopes on Earth it was largely red but the rest of the body was neutral coloured, like dirty snow.&#8220;Most of the surface reflects neutrally but one of its long faces has a large red region. This argues for broad compositional variations, which is unusual for such a small body,&#8221; said Fraser. The findings, published in the journal Nature Astronomy, have helped to build a more accurate profile of Oumuamua. &#8220;We now know that beyond its unusual elongated shape, this space cucumber had origins around another star, has had a violent past, and tumbles chaotically because of it,&#8221; Fraser said.&#8220;Our results are really helping to paint a more complete picture of this strange interstellar interloper. It is quite unusual compared to most asteroids and comets we see in our own solar system,&#8221; he said.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T21:27:33+00:00</date><place>London</place><tags /><catagory>Science</catagory></article><article><headline>Lightning storms to drop as global temperatures rise:&#160;Study</headline><description>Climate change could be set to impact lightning strikes, say researchers, which could affect atmospheric changes in temperature.</description><author>IANS</author><content>New research forecasts a 15 per cent drop in the average number of lightning flashes worldwide by the turn of this century, if global temperatures are in the top range of forecasts. The results, published in the journal Nature Climate Change, account for a five degree Celsius rise in global average temperatures by the year 2100.&#8220;This research expands our current knowledge of climate change impacts on lightning and suggests that in a warmer world, the incidence of lightning is likely to decrease,&#8221; said Professor Ruth Doherty of University of Edinburgh in Britain. Scientists estimate there are 1.4 billion lightning flashes each year around the world.A drop in the incidence of lightning strikes could impact on the frequency of wildfires, especially in tropical regions. It could also lower the incidence of lightning strikes to infrastructure and affect how greenhouse gases in the atmosphere contribute to climate change. For the study, the scientists used a newly-devised method to calculate the likely incidence of lightning flashes from storm clouds.Unlike traditional calculations of lightning flashes at the global scale, which are based on the height of clouds, their approach takes into account the movement of tiny ice particles that form and move within clouds. Electrical charges build up in these ice particles, and in cold water droplets and soft hail formed inside clouds. These are discharged during storms, giving rise to lightning flashes and thunder.The new study shows that on average lightning flashes are less likely in future, in contrast to previous studies. &#8220;These results suggest that lightning schemes more closely related to cloud ice and microphysical processes are needed to robustly estimate future changes in lightning and atmospheric composition,&#8221; the study said.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T20:28:10+00:00</date><place>London</place><tags>Lightning,University of Edinburgh</tags><catagory>Science</catagory></article><article><headline>Recycled telescope to help create 3D map of&#160;Universe</headline><description>A research group will use a 45-year-old telescope to create a 3D map of the Universe.</description><author>PTI</author><content>A 45-year-old telescope is being re-purposed to create the largest 3D map of the universe and solve the mystery of dark energy, which is believed to drive the accelerating expansion of the cosmos. Tucked inside a 14-story, 500-tonne dome atop a peak in Arizona, the telescope took in the night sky for the first time and recorded its observations in glass photographic plates.The temporary closure sets in motion the largest overhaul in the telescope&#8217;s history and sets the stage for the installation of the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI), which will begin a five-year observing run next year at the US National Science Foundation&#8217;s Kitt Peak National Observatory (KPNO) &#8211; part of the National Optical Astronomy Observatory (NOAO).&#8220;This day marks an enormous milestone for us,&#8221; said Michael Levi DESI Director of the US Department of Energy&#8217;s Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (Berkeley Lab). Now we remove the old equipment and start the yearlong process of putting the new stuff on,&#157; said Levi. More than 465 researchers from about 71 institutions are participating in the DESI collaboration.The entire top end of the telescope, its secondary mirror and a large digital camera, will be removed and replaced with DESI instruments. A large crane will lift the telescope&#8217;s top end through the observing slit in its dome.
Besides providing new insights about the universe&#8217;s expansion and large-scale structure, DESI will also help set limits on theories related to gravity and the formative stages of the universe, and could even provide new mass measurements for a variety of elusive yet abundant subatomic particles called neutrinos.&#8220;One of the primary ways that we learn about the unseen universe is by its subtle effects on the clustering of galaxies,&#157;&#8221; said Daniel Eisenstein of Harvard University in the US. &#8220;The new maps from DESI will provide an exquisite new level of sensitivity in our study of cosmology,&#8221; said Eisenstein. The Mayall Telescope has played an important role in many astronomical discoveries, including measurements supporting the discovery of dark energy and establishing the role of dark matter in the universe from measurements of galaxy rotation.Its observations have also been used in determining the scale and structure of the universe. Dark matter and dark energy together are believed to make up about 95 per cent of all of the universe&#8217;s mass and energy. It was one of the world&#8217;s largest optical telescopes at the time it was built, and because of its sturdy construction it is perfectly suited to carry the new 9-ton instrument.&#8220;We started this project by surveying large telescopes to find one that had a suitable mirror and wouldn&#8217;t collapse under the weight of such a massive instrument,&#8221;&#157; said David Schlegel a DESI project scientist at Berkeley Lab. The expansion of the telescope&#8217;s field-of-view will allow DESI to map out about one-third of the sky. Brenna Flaugher, a DESI project scientist who leads the Astrophysics Department at Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory, said DESI will transform the speed of science at the Mayall Telescope.&#8220;The telescope was designed to carry a person at the top who aimed and steered it, but with DESI it&#8217;s all automated,&#8221; Flaugher said. &#8220;Instead of one at a time we can measure the velocities of 5,000 galaxies at a time &#8211; we will measure more than 30 million of them in our five-year survey,&#8221; she said. DESI will use an array of 5,000 swivelling robots, each carefully choreographed to point a fibre-optic cable at a preprogrammed sequence of deep-space objects, including millions of galaxies and quasars, which are galaxies that harbour massive, actively feeding black holes.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T19:59:13+00:00</date><place>Washington</place><tags>telescope</tags><catagory>Science</catagory></article><article><headline>Valentine&#8217;s Day deal: Honor 7X, Honor View 10 to get 10% cashback, no cost EMI&#160;offer</headline><description>Honor View 10 is priced at Rs 29,999 in India, while pricing for Honor 7X starts at Rs 12,999 for the base 32GB storage model.</description><author>Tech Desk</author><content>Honor 7X and the Honor View 10 smartphones will be available with 10 per cent cashback and No cost EMI offers on Amazon India, starting Valentine&#8217;s Day, which is on February 14. The offer is a part of Amazon&#8217;s Valentine&#8217;s Week deals, that is valid till February 20. The cashback offer can only be availed by people who purchase the phone using ICICI Bank credit cards. Honor View 10 is priced at Rs 29,999 in India, while pricing for Honor 7X starts at Rs 12,999 for the base 32GB storage model. The 64GB storage option of Honor 7X costs Rs 15,999.In terms of specifications, the Honor View 10 gets a&#160;5.99-inch FHD+ Full View display with 18:9 aspect ratio. The phone is powered by Huawei&#8217;s Kirin 970 processor, that includes an Octa-core ARM Cortex CPU alongside the Mali-G72 12-core GPU. It comes with&#160;6GB RAM and 128GB internal storage, which is expandable up to 256GB via a microSD slot. Honor View 10 runs EMUI 8.0, which is based on Android 8.0 Oreo.&#160;Honor View 10 is backed by a 3,750 mAh battery with support for the company&#8217;s fast charging technology. The phone gets a dual rear camera setup, a combination of 16MP + 20MP lens with f/1.8 aperture. The front shooter is a 13MP one.The highlight of Honor View 10 is&#160;its focus on Artificial Intelligence. Honor View 10 is the company&#8217;s first smartphone with its
own chipset Kirin 970 which has a dedicated Neural Processing Unit (NPU) for AI related tasks. The company claims the Kirin 970 chipset is optimised for AI features like Facial recognition, live text translation using the camera etc. The chipset powers several artificially intelligent apps, that can recognise different scenes while taking photos and translate languages in real-time even when a user is offline.Honor 7X sports a 5.93-inch FHD+ Full View display and runs on Octa-core Hisilicon Kirin 659 processor. The smartphone ships with Android 7.0 Nougat-based EMUI 5.1. It packs a 3,340mAh battery. In terms of camera, there&#8217;s a combination of 16MP + 2MP rear lens with PDAF and LED flash. It supports an 8MP selfie camera. Honor 7X offers 4GB RAM with either 32GB or 64GB storage. Both the variants support expandable storage up to 256GB via a microSD slot.&#8220;Honor View 10 and Honor 7X have redefined the smartphone experience in their respective segments, owing to Honor&#8217;s advanced technology innovation and consumer centricity. Both smartphones have played an integral role in establishing Honor as the go-to smartphone brand in the Indian market and have set benchmarks for the competition,&#8221; said P Sanjeev, Vice President, Sales, Huawei Consumer Business Group.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T18:49:04+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place><tags>Amazon,Honor 7X,Honor View 10</tags><catagory>Mobile &amp; Tabs</catagory></article><article><headline>Commercial AI programmes show sexist, racist tendencies:&#160;Study</headline><description>A study of facial recognition systems, that are based on artificial intelligence, show that these systems function on colour-based and gender-based biases.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Commercial facial-analysis artificial intelligence programmes tend to demonstrate skin-type and gender biases, a study has found. In experiments, the error rates of three commercial programmes in determining the gender of light-skinned men were never worse than 0.8 per cent.For darker-skinned women, however, the error rates ballooned to more than 20 per cent in one case and more than 34 per cent in the other two. The findings raise questions about how today&#8217;s neural networks, which learn to perform computational tasks by looking for patterns in huge data sets, are trained and evaluated. For instance, researchers at a major US technology company claimed an accuracy rate of more than 97 per cent for a face-recognition system they&#8217;d designed.However, the data set used to assess its performance was more than 77 per cent male and more than 83 per cent white. &#8220;What&#8217;s really important here is the method and how that method applies to other applications,&#8221; said Joy Buolamwini, a researcher at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) in the US. &#8220;The same data-centric techniques that can be used to try to determine somebody&#8217;s gender are also used to identify a person when you&#8217;re looking for a criminal suspect or to unlock your phone,&#8221; said Buolamwini.&#8220;It&#8217;s not just about computer vision. I&#8217;m really hopeful that this will spur more work into looking at other disparities,&#8221; he said. The three programmes that researchers investigated were general-purpose facial-analysis systems, which could be used to match faces in different photos as well as to assess characteristics such as gender, age, and mood.All three systems treated gender classification as a binary decision &#8211; male or female &#8211; which made their performance on that task particularly easy to assess statistically. However, the same types of bias probably afflict the programmes&#8217; performance on other tasks, too. To begin investigating the programs&#8217; biases systematically, Buolamwini first assembled a set of images in which women and people with dark skin are much better-represented than they are in the data sets typically used to evaluate face-analysis systems. The final set contained more than 1,200 images.Next, she worked with a dermatologic surgeon to code the images according to the Fitzpatrick scale of skin tones, a six-point scale, from light to dark, originally developed by dermatologists as a means of assessing risk of sunburn. Then she applied three commercial facial-analysis systems from major technology companies to her newly constructed data set.Across all three, the error rates for gender classification were consistently higher for females than they were for males, and for darker-skinned subjects than for lighter-skinned subjects. For darker-skinned women, the error rates were 20.8 per cent, 34.5 per cent, and 34.7. But with two of the systems, the error rates for the darkest-skinned women in the data set were worse &#8211; 46.5 per cent and 46.8 per cent. Essentially, for those women, the system might as well have been guessing gender at random.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T18:28:31+00:00</date><place>Boston</place><tags>artificial intelligence,Massachusetts Institute of Technology</tags><catagory>Tech News</catagory></article><article><headline>New age-detecting system can set child locks on your&#160;smartphone</headline><description>A new study has been able to determine smartphone activities of children based on swiping patterns.</description><author>PTI</author><content>Parents, take note! Your smartphone may soon be able to tell if your toddler is swiping the screen and automatically block apps that are off-limits for kids. A number of existing smartphone apps aim to control kids&#8217; activity on phones, but could be disabled by tech-savvy children.Researchers from University of South Carolina in the US and Zhejiang University in China found that automated age-range detection would prevent kids from stumbling upon an inappropriate website or get into a work e-mail account. The researchers observed two big differences between how children and adults swipe phone screens.Since kids have smaller hands and shorter fingertips than adults, they often touch a smaller area on the screen and make shorter swipes, said Xiaopeng Li, a graduate student at the University of South Carolina. Children also tend to swipe their fingers more sluggishly across the screen, and they are slower to switch from swiping to tapping.To gather data on these differences, researchers built a simple app, the &#8216;MIT Technology Review&#8217; reported. They asked a group of kids between the ages of three and 11, and a group of adults between 22 and 60 to use it. The app had participants unlock an Android phone and then play a numbers-based game on it, so that the researchers could record a variety of taps and swipes. They also tracked things like the amount of pressure applied by a user&#8217;s finger and the area it encompassed.The resulting data was used to train an age-detecting algorithm that they say is 84 per cent accurate with just one swipe on the screen &#8211; a figure that goes up to 97 per cent after eight swipes.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:39:15+00:00</date><place>Washington</place><tags>smartphones</tags><catagory>Mobile &amp; Tabs</catagory></article><article><headline>Reliance JioPhone will get its own Facebook app from February&#160;14</headline><description>Reliance JioPhone, which has managed to capture the top share in India's feature phone market, will now have its own Facebook app. JioPhone's Facebook app will be ready to download from February 14.</description><author>Tech Desk</author><content>Reliance JioPhone, which has managed to capture the top share in India&#8217;s feature phone market, will now have its own Facebook app. Jio confirmed that the Facebook will be available on the Jio feature phone from February 14, which is tomorrow. According to Jio, this new version of the Facebook app is built specially for Jio KaiOS, which is what powers the JioPhone. The company states the inclusion of Facebook on JioPhone will open up the social network to potential 50 crore feature phone users in India.According to Jio, the Facebook app on the JioPhone will show notifications, videos, and links to external content. The company also claims the app has been also optimised to successfully accommodate the cursor function on JioPhone. News Feed, Photos, etc will be supported on the Facebook app on Jio Phone. The Facebook App will be available on the JioPhone App store for downloads. Currently the JioPhone is limited to apps from the telecom player itself.Previously Google had announced a version of its Google voice assistant for the JioPhone, though it has yet to roll out. The Google Assistant for JioPhone was announced in December 2017 at the Google for India event. Earlier leaks and reports have also claimed that WhatsApp, which is owned by Facebook, will also have a version for the JioPhone.&#8220;As promised, JioPhone will be home to the world&#8217;s leading applications, starting with Facebook. Jio, the world&#8217;s largest mobile data network, is built to empower every Indian with the power of data and JioPhone is an integral part of this Jio movement,&#8221; said Akash Ambani, Director, Jio in a press statement.&#8220;We are excited about our partnership with Jio and the opportunity to provide the best possible Facebook experience for millions of people using JioPhone. Working with partners like Jio, we want to make sure everyone, everywhere has the opportunity to enjoy the benefits of being connected,&#8221;&#160;Francisco Varela, Vice President of Mobile Partnerships, Facebook said in a press statement.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:22:56+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place><tags>JioPhone,Reliance JioPhone</tags><catagory>Mobile &amp; Tabs</catagory></article><article><headline>&#8216;Olympic Destroyer&#8217; malware targeted PyeongChang Games: Cyber security&#160;firms</headline><description>Cyber security firms Cisco, FireEye and CrowdStrike have confirmed that they discovered malware, dubbed Olympic Destroyer', which affected the Games' opening ceremony.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Several US cyber security firms said on Monday that they had uncovered a computer virus dubbed &#8216;Olympic Destroyer&#8217; that was likely used in an attack on Friday&#8217;s opening ceremony of the Pyeongchang Winter Games. Games Organizers confirmed the attack on Sunday, saying that it affected internet and television services but did not compromise critical operations. Organizers did not say who was behind the attack or provide detailed discussion of the malware, though a spokesman said that all issues had been resolved as of Saturday.Researchers with cyber security firms Cisco Systems Inc, CrowdStrike and FireEye Inc said in blog posts and statements to Reuters on Monday that they had analysed computer code they believed was used in Friday&#8217;s attack. All three security companies said the Olympic Destroyer malware was designed to knock computers offline by deleting critical system files, which would render the machines useless. The three firms said they did not know who was behind the attack.&#8220;Disruption is the clear objective in this type of attack and it leaves us confident in thinking that the actors behind this were after embarrassment of the Olympic committee during the opening ceremony,&#8221; Cisco said in its blog. The attack took the Olympics website offline, which meant that some people could not print out tickets and Wi-Fi used by reporters covering the games did not work during the opening ceremony, according to Cisco.The attack did not affect the performance of drones, which were initially scheduled to be included in the opening ceremony, but later pulled from the program, organizers said in a statement. The drone light show was cancelled because there were too many spectators standing in the area where it was supposed to take place, the statement said.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T17:12:48+00:00</date><place /><tags>2018 Winter Olympics,cyber security,malware</tags><catagory>Tech News</catagory></article><article><headline>Xiaomi leads India&#8217;s smartphone market, Samsung slips to number two: IDC&#160;report</headline><description>Xiaomi emerged as the number one smartphone vendor in the Q4, 2017 for India, beating South-Korean major Samsung, according to the latest data shared by IDC.</description><author>Shruti Dhapola</author><content>Xiaomi emerged as the number one smartphone vendor in the Q4, 2017 for the Indian market, beating South-Korean major Samsung, according to the latest data shared by International Data Corporation (IDC). However, IDC&#8217;s report showed that for 2017 as a whole, Samsung was still the leading smartphone vendor in the country, with Xiaomi close at number two. IDC&#8217;s report is similar to what other research firms like Canalys, Counterpoint have reported about the Indian smartphone market, which have also pegged Xiaomi has emerged as the number one vendor.According to IDC, the Indian smartphone market saw a&#160;&#8220;healthy 14 percent annual growth&#8221; and total shipments for the year 2017 stood at 124 million. IDC also said that India is the &#8220;fastest growing market&#8221; among the top 20 smartphone markets globally. However, Q4 2017 saw a sharp dip of 22 per cent&#160;quarter-over-quarter, according to the firm. It should be remembered the third quarter in India is the festival season with Diwali, other festivals taking place, which also explains the dip in Q4. But the yearly growth for Q4, 2017 stood at 18 per cent, notes IDC, with Chinese brands continuing to dominate.&#8220;The untapped demand in the lower-tier cities remains the key attraction for China-based brands to explore the growth trajectory in India. Their strength in their home market of China and weakening position of local players has helped some of these China-based players to solidify their operations in India, Jaipal Singh, Senior Market Analyst, IDC India said in a press statement.Also read: Xiaomi Redmi Note 5 India launch on February 14: Livestream time, expected price, specsAccording to IDC, India is now the&#160;world&#8217;s third largest smartphone market, but it is still the world&#8217;s biggest feature phone market as well. In fact, according to IDC feature phones saw a 17 per cent yearly growth in 2017, thanks to the Reliance JioPhone.&#160; India&#8217;s feature phone shipments stood at 164 million feature phone shipments for 2017, a rise from the 140 million shipments in 2016.On the smartphone segment, IDC noted that Xiaomi and Jio&#8217;s growth was due to the aggressive pricing strategy. &#8220;Xiaomi&#8217;s offline expansion and higher marketing spends were other key factors for the vendor&#8217;s high shipments in the seasonally low quarter,&#8221; added&#160;Upasana Joshi, Senior Market Analyst, IDC India.In terms of market share for Q4, 2017, Xiaomi was on top with 26.8 per cent market share while Samsung had 24.2 per cent. vivo was number three with 6.5 per cent share, while Lenovo (includes Motorola) had 5.6 per cent market share. Oppo was number five on the list with 4.9 per cent of market share.According to IDC, Xiaomi saw its shipments triple year-over-year and the company sold more than 2 million units from its offline channel, where it has been expanding base. Samsung &#8220;faced challenges in competing with the aggressive pricing strategy of Xiaomi in India,&#8221; according to the research firm, which notes that the brand still enjoy strong channel trust.Chinese player vivo saw a 41 per cent decline from the previous quarter and remained flat on yearly growth, even though it managed to stay as number three in the market. Lenovo (including Motorola) was down to number four as its shipments fell in Q4. Shipments for the Lenovo-branded phones declined almost 60 per cent, while Motorola portfolio saw a marginal increase compared to 2016, according to IDC.&#160; Finally, Oppo managed to hold on to the number five position, though it shipments dropped almost by half compared to the previous quarter.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:54:36+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place><tags>Samsung,Xiaomi</tags><catagory>Mobile &amp; Tabs</catagory></article><article><headline>Reliance Jio&#8217;s JioFiber broadband service to launch by March end:&#160;Report</headline><description>Reliance Jio's JioFiber broadband service is expected to go live by the end of this quarter.</description><author>Tech Desk</author><content>Reliance Jio&#8217;s JioFiber broadband service is expected to go live by the end of this quarter, according to a report in Telecomtalk.info. If the latest information is to be believed, users will be able to experience Jio&#8217;s high-speed broadband Internet by the end March. The JioFiber service is long-awaited and is supposed to be the next big thing for the company since the rollout of its 4G LTE service network in September 2016.Reliance Jio&#8217;s Fiber Preview offer has already been rolled out in select areas of Mumbai, Delhi-NCR, Ahmedabad, Jamnagar, Surat and Vadodara. Testing had begun in some select residential colonies in the city of Chennai in September 2016. As far as pricing goes, the company is&#160;expected to go for the disruptive pricing model, just like it did with the Jio mobile network.The details of the JioFiber service was previously leaked on Jio&#8217;s official website. At the time of the launch, Jio could offer 100GB of data per month at 100 Mbps speed for three months, which will be effectively free.&#160;Reliance Jio could ask for a refundable seucrity deposit of Rs 4,500 for its service. Post exhaustion of 100GB, speed will go down to 1 Mbps. Reports have also suggested that Jio could offer 100GB data at just Rs 500 post its three-month complimentary service.With Reliance Jio&#8217;s JioFiber, users should be able to stream 4K content and connect multiple devices to JioFiber to enjoy high-speed Internet. Along side the JioFiber broadband service, the company is expected to launch a bouquet of services such as DTH, smart-TV boxes and IoT solutions.&#160;Jio&#8217;s DTH TV services could support more than 360 channels, and a &#8220;seven-day catch up option being given to users&#8221; as well.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:50:07+00:00</date><place>New Delhi</place><tags>Reliance Jio</tags><catagory>Tech News</catagory></article><article><headline>UK unveils tool for blocking extremist&#160;content</headline><description>The British government will be able to detect and remove extremist content from social media through a new tool, suggest reports.</description><author>IANS</author><content>The British government has unveiled a tool that can accurately detect extremist content and block it from being viewed, the media reported on Tuesday. Home Secretary Amber Rudd told the BBC that she would not rule out forcing technology companies to use it by law.Rudd visited the US to meet tech companies to discuss the idea, as well as other efforts to tackle extremism. The tool was made as a way to demonstrate that the government&#8217;s demand for a clampdown on extremist activity was not unreasonable, Rudd said.&#8220;It&#8217;s a very convincing example of the fact that you can have the information you need to make sure this material doesn&#8217;t go online in the first place,&#8221; she told the BBC. Thousands of hours of content posted by the Islamic State (IS) terror group was run past the tool, in order to &#8216;train&#8217; it to automatically spot extremist material.The government provided 600,000 pounds ($832,000) of public funds towards the creation of the tool by an artificial intelligence company based in London. According to ASI Data Science, the software is capable of detecting 94 per cent of IS&#8217;s online activity, with an accuracy of 99.995 per cent.The Global Internet Forum to Counter Terrorism, launched last year, brings together several governments including the US and UK, and major internet firms like Facebook, Google, Twitter and others. However, the bigger challenge is predicting which parts of the internet the terrorists will use next.The Home Office estimates that between July and the end of 2017, extremist material appeared in almost 150 web services that had not been used for such propaganda before.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:54:20+00:00</date><place>London</place><tags>extremism,Social media</tags><catagory>Social</catagory></article><article><headline>Snapchat&#8217;s popularity among kids helps draw&#160;advertisers</headline><description>In the midst of heated rivalry between Snapchat and Instagram, the increased popularity among youth has helped advertisers pick the Snap Inc's photo-sharing platform.</description><author>Reuters</author><content>Social network Instagram has come to look more like rival Snapchat after copying some of its features, but marketers say Snapchat&#8217;s younger audience and safeguards against poor placement drive enthusiasm for advertising on the smaller app.Expectations for Snapchat&#8217;s future tumbled with its stock price after an initial public offering last year, mainly over doubts that Snapchat could compete against Instagram, but last week, Snap reported a 72 percent rise in quarterly revenue that beat analysts&#8217; forecasts and re-ignited confidence. Snapchat, owned by Snap Inc, retains an advantage with the millennial generation who popularized its disappearing messages and animated face masks, despite attempts by Facebook Inc-owned Instagram to woo them away, advertising executives say.The advantage among young people is even expected to widen this year, at least in the United States, according to estimates released on Monday by research firm eMarketer. This year, Instagram will add 1.6 million Americans under 25, while Snapchat will add 1.9 million in the age group, eMarketer said. The different demographics mean businesses feel obligated to spend on Snapchat even if they already do so on Instagram, said Aaron Shapiro, chief executive of digital marketing firm Huge. &#8220;It&#8217;s all people who are reaching youth,&#8221; Shapiro said of Snapchat&#8217;s strength. Facebook, Instagram and Snapchat declined to comment on the eMarketer figures.One section of Snapchat is also perceived among marketers as a potential haven from the amateur posts that define much of social media, created by users or aspiring internet stars rather than by professionals at media companies.
One of the ways that advertisers said Snapchat has distinguished itself is the app&#8217;s &#8216;discover&#8217; tab, a prominent section of the app that spotlights short videos from outlets such as ESPN or the New York Times. Snapchat chooses which outlets to work with, giving advertisers some assurance their video ads will run adjacent to professionally developed shows, not less predictable user-generated content.&#8220;Snapchat can provide a highly controlled environment for advertisers to reach an audience,&#8221; said Nick Cicero, chief executive of Delmondo, a firm that advises corporate brands on social media advertising. Instagram has an &#8216;explore&#8217; tab with some professional content but no equivalent of Snapchat&#8217;s &#8216;discover&#8217; tab. Instagram&#8217;s sibling app Facebook has a &#8216;watch&#8217; tab that is more similar but is less than six months old.Instagram and Snapchat, both built around the smartphone camera, have been locked in a rivalry that heated up in 2016, when Instagram copied the popular Snapchat feature known as &#8216;stories.&#8217; The feature allows people to post photos and video that disappear after 24 hours. Advertisers are rooting for Snapchat and for Twitter Inc to succeed, Shapiro added, so that they do not need to rely so much on the largest internet advertising platforms, Facebook and Alphabet Inc&#8217;s Google.Interest in Facebook is waning among young Americans, eMarketer said in its note on Monday, estimating a 5.8 percent decline this year in Facebook US users aged 18 to 24 years. Still, Snapchat remains behind Instagram in some features that advertisers want. A business cannot, for example, create a fixed profile page on Snapchat to host photos and collect a data-rich list of fans the way it can on Instagram.Business pages make Instagram a &#8216;mobile visual shop,&#8217; Facebook Chief Operating Officer Sheryl Sandberg said last month, adding that two-thirds of visits to Instagram business profiles were from people who do not follow them.
In other ways, though, Snapchat is catching up. The company has in the past year transitioned to a self-serve ad system with pricing based on an auction, which marketers said has made buying much easier especially for smaller advertisers. Facebook and Instagram already have such systems.For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App</content><date>2018-02-13T16:12:07+00:00</date><place>San Francisco</place><tags>instagram,Snapchat</tags><catagory>Social</catagory></article></technology>
</news>